[Music]
Hey, hey, hey.
Heat.
[Music]
Heat. N.
Heat. Heat.
[Music]
Welcome Living Mana Church family. So
happy that you are here with us today on
the Sabbath to worship with us. Sorry
for the delay, but you stuck it out and
you are here. So, praise God that you
are here. We're so happy to have you
here. Because of time, I'm not going to
be able to do uh welcome specifically to
every person or not every person, but
many people in all the different areas,
but please still put in the chat um so
we all can see where you are viewing
from. Um but we're just trying to make
the best of our time because we still
have a Sabbath school panel. We want to
get into all of that. We have membership
transfers and so we want to be able to
do that as well. But again, welcome. We
are happy that you are here and you are
worshiping with us today. Praise God.
>> Yeah, we are going to be continuing our
Sabbath school on uh the Christian art
of war. We're going to be talking about
uh we're going to be getting into
chapter three today and uh so we are uh
looking forward to that. We've got our
guests back with us and uh we believe
it's going to be a blessing. You guys
are going to be um I think we're all
going to be blessed by what we talk
about today. We're gonna be talking
about David's Mighty Men.
>> Yes.
>> One of my favorite uh subjects when it
comes to this particular theme. So
>> I Yes. And I love that story. Yeah. This
is going to be exciting. So we want to
take our time with it as well. So we are
excited about that.
>> Um want to jump right into these
membership transfers that we have today.
So, we're just so thankful
that so many people want to join Living
Manage Church and we want to get to that
at uh this time. Okay, so we have a
first reading. Amen. For and we've got
to meet James and Michelle. This is
James and Michelle Kendrick from the
Clear Lake Seventh Day Adventist Church.
Uh that's in California. and they are
wanting to transfer their membership to
Living Mana Church. And so that's
exciting. We got to meet them a few
about about a month ago in California.
So that is great. We're so happy that
you guys are going to be official
members here at Living Man Church.
>> Amen.
>> And then this is a sad one. Let's see.
This is a first reading from uh Lisa
Copedge going and she is going to
uh Gordon Heights 7th Day Adventist
Church. I believe this is a reading from
I you know what I believe I'm reading
this right. She's she's transferring her
membership to Gordon Heights 7th Day
Adventist Church from Living Manage
Church. And that's Lisa Copedge. If I
got that wrong, Sister Patrice, please
text me and I will restate that. But I
believe that I'm correct in that. So we
have uh James and Michelle Kendrick uh
their first reading coming into the
church and then we have uh Lisa Copedge
going to Gordon Heights 7th Day
Adventist Church.
>> Those are both first readings.
>> Those are first readings. So yes. All
right. So, and we are thankful um that
so many people want to come in and we're
sad to see people go, but we know for
different reasons you have to go to
especially if you have children and
things like that and you want them um in
other places and for other reasons, but
we are happy to have everyone here at
Living Man.
>> Amen. Amen.
>> So, thank you. You guys are putting it
in the chat. Continue to put where
you're viewing from in the chat. Again,
we still see it. I just don't have time
to to shout everybody out, but we're so
happy that you are here. I want you to
do t-shirt message.
>> All right. So, the t-shirt message is
where God guides, he provides.
>> Yes, he does. And I was of course
thinking about what the message which
shirt I would wear and how it like what
am I feeling connected with? And you
know, it was this shirt. And you know
why I'm connected to this message? What?
>> Because I was thinking because I woke up
this morning thinking one week we will
have been married for 27 years. Mhm.
>> And that is like I know we all know
about your testimony, but us coming
together and um is a testimony in
itself. So I was just really thanking
God like where he guided you and how he
guided me so specifically so our paths
could cross. Yeah.
>> You know, I I wasn't a list person like
I was praying that I didn't want I
wanted I was praying to God
>> not to bring me a husband right at that
time because I was just really actually
happy with God me and God at that time.
I was happy not being with anyone. But
um I was praying. I wasn't a list girl.
I didn't have a list like it has to be
all. It wasn't that. But I was praying
and uh he guided you. He guided us on
the same path. And so he he provided
exactly who I needed.
>> Amen.
>> And so I can say
>> that he guided me to make some decisions
because if I didn't listen to his voice,
I would have missed you. We would not
have met.
>> And um and I can say the same thing for
you. He He definitely was guiding you.
So, yeah, that's why I did this t-shirt
today.
>> I like the t-shirt.
>> So, trust trust God and listen to his
voice because where he guides, he will
provide all of your needs.
>> Amen.
>> All right. So, now with that, we're
going to jump right into our Sabbath
school because this is going to be good.
>> Let's pray.
>> Do it.
>> Yeah.
>> Heavenly Father, thank you, Lord, for
your mercy and grace towards us, Lord.
And today, Lord, as we um continue our
study in the Christian Art of War, we
pray, Lord, that you would uh just guide
our thoughts, guide our guests, and uh
may the words we share. May the insights
we we share uh and insights that we gain
as we're sharing, Lord, be a blessing to
those watching. We thank you, Lord, for
hearing and answering because we ask it
in Jesus' name. Amen.
>> Amen. Amen. And while they're coming,
I'm going to fix my earpiece so I can
hear them.
>> Right.
So, we're going to welcome our guests.
>> Yes.
>> And um
>> welcome our guests. We're excited.
>> Again, we are picking up on um the third
chapter. So, we've covered chapters one
and two. Chapter two was a pretty short
chapter.
>> Yeah.
>> So, we were able to, you know, actually
do it in one setting. Um so, chapter
three, chapter three, we might be camped
out here for a little while.
>> That's good. This is one of my favorite
story. Well, that's good.
>> Yeah. Um,
>> I won't mind that at all.
Yes. So, this Yes. All right. Welcome.
Hey, Michaela. It's been a minute. How
are you? We've missed you.
>> Good.
>> Yes. Well, we are happy that you're
back. Welcome. Good to see you again,
Melinda
Kashif, Brother Terry, Pastor Lewami.
Good to see you guys here with us. We're
excited. We are excited.
>> Amen. Yes, we are. And we are getting
ready to jump in, you guys. So, here's
what I'm going to do. Um, I'm going to
just, uh, let we want to move through
chapter three,
uh, you know, methodically. So,
>> yeah, we don't want to rush. We're
taking our time. We have no, we don't
have to rush.
>> Yeah. The very the very first uh thing
that we deal with in chapter 3 is kind
of like this imaginary story of a
soldier who has just come home from the
battlefield. He's talking to his wife
about what he just experienced that day
and um and
his son
is listening to the conversation. Mhm.
>> So, let's just jump in and talk about
that first. I'm just going to see what
you know for our guests, what were your
thoughts as you were reading that
imaginary
uh conversation.
Um
cuz I know for me every time I sh I do
that sermon that just kind of is to me
one of the most like
>> imagine that. Imagine that. So,
uh whoever would like to share first on
that specific point. Um, and maybe if
you have nothing, if that didn't jump
out to you, that's fine, too. I know it
just jumped out to me. If y'all don't
say anything, I'll say something in the
chat for sure.
>> But, uh, but go ahead. Go ahead. Anybody
want to want to want to share on their
thoughts on on that? And let's explain
what that was, what that chap, what that
in what that discussion was. So, who who
wants to jump in and share?
>> Don't be shy.
All right. Well,
>> all right.
>> It's like um while I was reading that, I
was I was I thinking to myself, you
know, um you know, that that must have
been really really cool for a child to
hear, you know, because especially when
you put yourself in their in their
situation, you know, they have no no
internet, no anything. They don't they
don't know what Goliath looks like. Um
they they may not know what David looked
like at the time. And I start thinking
to myself, well,
I wonder when did I start
looking at Jesus like a a hero
>> in that sense?
>> Was it from as a child? Cuz you know,
you you grew up hearing about Jesus. You
know, you're taught that he loves you
and you should love him and you should
obey him and and all this stuff. And
then you think, um, but when did I
actually
start really viewing Christ the way that
he's supposed to be viewed in my life?
>> And then, um,
you start thinking because one of the
characters in the Bible that was big to
me was was Enoch. You know, it said
Enoch walked with God and that's why he
was translated. So I always used to like
think about that a lot like man how can
I reach to that point where God wants to
translate me
>> because there's there's no difference he
he's a man just like me
>> and then I was like wait why am I
focusing on Enoch so much
>> and Christ walked without sin completely
>> so that's where it led me when I was
reading it.
>> Yeah. Yeah. Yeah. That's good. That's
good. And you know, I may as well
explain the story because
our audience, if you haven't read this
chapter yet, you're like, "What are you
talking about?" Hopefully, you all have
to have the PDF. So, let me just let me
just
>> And let me just announce that really
quick. For those who are just joining us
for the first time, you can get the PDF.
What we're doing is we're going through
the Christian Art of War, uh the book
that Pastor Myers uh wrote about 17
years ago, but we um have the PDF of the
book in Mighty Networks. And so we've
released all the first three chapters so
you all can get that. So yeah, just um
just in case if you want to get it and
and follow along with us.
>> So okay, so this
uh this the beginning of the chapter is
about a little boy. He sees his father
come home. His father has this
bewildered look on his face. He's
excited but bewildered at the same time.
And he's talking to his wife and the kid
is just overhearing. He's like he's
like, "Honey, you will not believe what
happened today." And then I begin to
talk about how the kid hears his father
explaining, you know that giant, right?
The one that we that has been
threatening the army for the last 40
days and the child is like, he knows
about Goliath. All the kids have heard
about Goliath, right? And then he hears
a story of a little boy, maybe not too
much older than him, who comes out and
is defiant to the giant.
>> And
he
in his mind, he's thinking, did this
little boy get killed? Like, what
happened? And as he's listening to the
story
and he hears his father telling him that
this little boy
uh threw a rock
and it and caused the giant to fall and
then went and took a sword and killed
him with the sword like severed his
head.
And the kid must be like,
>> I
wait a minute, a kid my age.
>> Yeah.
>> And then I began to explain how from
that day on, every day the kids in the
backyard with like sticks and stones
practicing
>> to become a mighty man. And then
>> years later when David's army begins to
form,
>> you know, the idea is that it is these
young boys, right, who
>> who heard about David's story
that ultimately become
the mighty men that are described in
this chapter.
>> Yes.
>> So to me that was just something that
was very like man significant. They they
and and the parallel is that we
should be looking at Jesus as our hero.
>> We want to fight like him.
>> Right.
>> Right. We want to train like him. And so
that's kind of the idea behind the
introduction of this chapter and then
we're going to go into the attributes of
these mighty men.
>> So, all right. With that laid out, now
I'll ask anyone else. Anyone else want
to jump in and just talk about that
section? Yes. Um before we before we
move into some of the specific
attributes of these mighty men.
>> Okay. I guess
>> when I was
>> Who was that talking? Somebody. Yeah.
>> Yes, that was Melissa. Sorry.
>> Oh, it wasn't you. Oh, it was Michaela.
Okay, my M&M's. I got both back. Okay,
let's go. Michaela.
>> Um, when I was reading that,
just imagining it that story in that
way, like
they had all the miracle stories from
the Exodus and all that, but then this
is something that your own dad saw. This
was something that was happening right
then, something you could personally
relate to. And
I think looking at Jesus like that,
looking at all these stories like that
is like what makes them so impactful
>> because that's what really inspired
um people in David's day and mighty men
and
what should be inspiring us just looking
at Jesus like that like it's very
personal very
impactful
art hero. I just I love that. That's the
goal.
>> So, um Michaela, I I just uh
I was just looking in the chat and
someone put something in the chat that
you know just has made me pause and I'm
already thinking sermon material.
>> Oh boy. But uh wow, David use a stone to
destroy the giant and uh
um
sungazing just said for the first time I
just connected the stone making the
giant fall being like the stone that
makes the giant statue fall in Daniel
chapter 2. M
>> and that's pretty crazy.
>> Mhm.
>> Uh because we're talking about wanting
to be like our hero,
>> right?
>> Right.
>> And in this story in chapter 3 uh of
this chap of uh of the Christian art of
war, we're looking at David and how he
used the stone to defeat the giant. And
because of that, whoa, that's our hero.
M
>> in the same way Jesus who in the future
destroys the giant but this time with a
stone to the to the foot
>> to the feet.
>> Yes.
>> That's our hero.
>> We ought to want to be like him.
>> And so I think that's a powerful
>> Wow. I've never seen that before. And
sungazing. That's pretty powerful. Just
adding it into what we're talking about
right now. Mhm.
>> We should be those kids that are like,
"Wait, that's the stone. I want to be
like that stone. I want to be like
Jesus."
>> Amen.
>> Amen. Amen.
>> Wow.
>> So, okay. I don't know if someone else
was going to say something as Melinda
was was sharing or what.
>> Michaela.
>> Oh, Michaela just shared. You said
Melinda.
>> Michaela. I'm sorry.
>> Michaela. Michaela. So, was someone else
going to jump in and say something?
>> Yeah. Um,
Terry, hi everyone. Uh, yeah, you know,
um,
I'm commuting to work again, so I get a
lot more time to think and meditate and
listen to messages and stuff. And I
began to realize this little imaginary
story may be a whole lot more profound
than I first re, you know, realized it
was. And so, uh, as I'm going to work,
you know, the Lord kind of laid, uh,
Psalm 11 on my heart again. You know,
uh, blessed is the man that walketh not
in the counsel of ungodly, nor standeth
in the way of sinners, nor siteth in the
seat of the scornful, but his delight is
in the law of the Lord, and in his law
does he meditate day and night. And so,
as I was meditating, the Lord was like,
this is very profound because no mighty
man just wakes up one day and he's a
mighty man. there's something in the
foundational years of his life that gave
him his why that pastor Law was talking
about why why am I doing what I'm doing
you know and so on the one hand in my
case you know I grew up I didn't have a
father in the home and who were my
heroes you know who was going to be that
example for me what was going to get me
motivated to move in that right
direction because as the book mentioned
these young men were so inspired by
their father who was also a military man
and he comes back and tells this amazing
story about David. And so somewhere that
moved them towards direction of okay,
I'm going to start cultivating the
skills. I'm going to start thinking
about the strategies. I'm going to start
developing into one day I'm going to
join this awesome young boy David just
like me, you know. So
>> really profound stuff. And I think we if
the more time we spend there listening
to the Lord, he's going to bring out a
lot of stuff that shows us the
importance of train up a child in the
way that you go and when he's old, he
will not depart from it.
>> There's a lot there. Amen.
>> Amen.
>> Amen. All right. Anybody else want to
want to add a thought in there uh on
this particular section before we move
on?
>> All right. Yeah, I don't know if there's
a delay.
>> One one thing.
>> Yeah, go ahead.
>> One thing I could share.
>> Um, and if I'm off, let me know. But
these mighty warriors are simply a
reflection of the man that they're
following. Right.
>> So,
>> they have to be representatives
and mere copies of the very person that
they are following. Yeah.
>> Right. So what David demonstrated, these
men will have to demonstrate as well.
And that's something that I just wanted
to kind of pinpoint as uh brother Terry
was sharing that these men, these mighty
warriors are literally a reflection of
the men that they are following, their
commander-in-chief.
>> Yeah.
>> And and you know, Lamei, that that
>> that is a a pretty important thought in
and of itself because just think about
it.
When you look at the things that these
mighty men did,
any one of them could have been like,
you know,
why not me?
>> Yeah.
>> Why not me?
>> Amen. Amen.
>> Um, yeah, David's, you know, slew the
giant, but uh, look at what I'm doing.
Mhm.
>> And there's something to speak that's
something to speak to that
their dedication
to a hero, right?
Um and to the Lord.
>> Yeah.
>> Because they knew, hey, this is the man
that the Lord has chosen.
>> This is not saying that, you know, I
don't think any of them were actually
mightier than David. I mean, I think for
all that all that these men did,
>> like I think David was I the Bible
doesn't say so, I don't think, but I
think David still could have taken all
of them,
>> right?
>> But and again, I don't know. I don't
know. But I'm just saying that think
about how powerful these men were, the
mighty feats that they did. And
um I know Omari, let me just let me just
pause for a second. I need to talk about
photo theology just for a second. Okay?
>> Because I I need people to understand
that there are so many pictures,
beautiful pictures in the Bible.
>> You can't see them all as one person. So
someone just said, "I would have thought
Pastor Mars would have seen that years
ago with his photo theology." And I'm
like, "Me too, y'all. Me too. I would
have thought too. How how profound
>> of a of a thought is that?
>> And so it's just to say
that just as God uses David,
>> he has other men that he can make
mighty, right?
>> Yes. Oh, yes.
>> In the same way, oh, you know, it would
take Pastor M to cover that. No, no, no,
no, no. There's other God wants other
mighty men in the scriptures, right?
Mighty men and mighty women in the
scriptures. And
>> so I just freestyle that little thing
right there. But you get the idea. You
get the idea. So
my point was that these men for all the
the the the skill they had
>> never sought to usurp God's authority
>> or to say to themselves, "Why not me?"
>> Yes.
>> Like it was just like, you know,
>> they just probably never even imagined
like why would I ever why would I ever
try to go up against David?
>> Right. Right?
>> Why would I ever fight
>> the man that I love,
>> right? The man that I that I uh
>> honor and respect,
>> the man of the Lord.
>> So, okay, go ahead. We'll bring a guest
on uh to to just amplify that point or
or speak to that. Um anybody else want
to share?
>> So,
>> yeah. Can I circle back?
>> Go ahead. Sorry. Go ahead.
>> No,
>> no, no. Go ahead.
>> Okay. Okay. So, um, something that I
thought was extremely interesting is
that
David isn't going out to face the giant
in armor.
He's coming with five stones and a
staff.
And usually when I think of battle, now
on the spiritual level, of course, as
we're applying this to David, but when I
think of battle, I think of the Lord's
armor. But in this case, David isn't
even wearing anything. He's just having
his stones and his staff. And that was
interesting to me. I don't know how to
how to really
categorize that because usually I don't
know. What do you guys think?
>> Could you could you repeat that?
Um, was my mic off or?
>> No, no, no, no, no. I heard you, but I
want I want to get a clearer picture of
what you're saying or what you're
asking.
>> Okay, sure. So, I was wondering why is
David coming out without armor? Because
usually when I think of battle, I think
armor of the Lord, especially in the
spiritual sense. But David is coming out
with a rod and stones. Anybody
want to try to tackle that?
>> Yeah, I there there's a big I believe
that there's a big message that is being
articulated where David relied on what
he utilized to win his battles.
Saul was offering his battle, his his
armor to fight a battle that David is
not familiar with. I know that I've
protected my sheep. I've defeated bears
and lions with what I have in my hand. I
don't need your armor to be able to
fight the battle that God has called me
to fight. I'm going to rely on what has
gotten me the victory up to this point.
And I think that's so it's applicable
because so often when we are engaging in
this warfare against self and the battle
against good and evil, we often try to
give people our armor when it's not what
they have used to overcome their
victories.
David had to default to what he knew
>> he needed to conquer this giant.
>> I can't use your armor. I've never I've
never operated using something that I'm
unfamiliar with. And I think that is
what the message that God wants to
articulate through that story that with
David, you have to rely on the victories
that you've had and what you have
utilized to be able to have victory in
those battles that now when you face a
giant, you're not relying or dependent
on others or other things. You're simply
dependent on what God has used up to
that point.
>> Amen. Amen.
>> Amen. That makes sense.
>> Amen.
I think
>> you know pastor I think
>> I think also like in David's mind in
some ways the giant was already like
defeated
in some ways cuz like he's like you
defied God and now in God's name
you can't do that. You just can't do
that. So, you're already defeated. And
>> man,
>> so
I I kind of feel like maybe he's like,
"This isn't going to do any good. This
is going to be more impactful." Um, and
just God doing it versus all this
superfluous
armor maybe.
That's good. That's good. Terry, were
you gonna Were you going to jump in and
add something?
>> Yeah. I I just think we're on something
really really heavy right here. Um um
this morning in the pre-ervice prayer,
someone said I think it was Sister
Denise. She said that on this panel, we
have old meeting young.
>> I don't know who the old is because I'm
young, but me and me and the M&M's are
all young. But she was saying we have
old meeting young. And it's so powerful
in this story, pastor, this imaginary
story, and it's probably not imaginary
at all. It's probably exactly how it
happened with these mighty men. So, we
see them as mighty men,
>> but through the story God's given you in
the book, we get to fill in the gap
where it all started, right?
>> And so, someone mentioned a moment ago,
they didn't have internet and all that,
so they couldn't see the giant out there
and all that. And so in today's world,
you know, what are the messages that our
children are getting, our youth are
getting if if they're in a broken home,
maybe a dysfunctional home, and a dad's
not there, but are they getting it
through um social media? They're getting
it through entertainment or getting
through what what what helps them to
develop their identity and their their
value and worth and who they want to be.
Where do they get that from? Right?
>> And I love what Pastor Lame was saying.
You know, I don't need the world's
armor. I don't need the world's
influences. God, what I have is what I
need. And our young people can know,
hey, look, you can be a mighty man and
look where it starts. It starts right
where you are right now. It's okay.
You're okay. And what you have, God can
take that and use that to do great and
awesome things right where you are. And
I think, wow, what a message, pastor.
Uh, beautiful stuff. because it's so
easy for me to want to go out and be be
like, you know, someone else and think
that maybe I'm not good enough. And
there's a lot that goes over in our
lives, a lot of trauma, a lot of things
that happen, you know, like for for
example, when I go to the to the David's
mighty men and I first read that before
the Lord gave me the principles of, you
know, healthy confrontation and therapy
like first lady teaches and and and and
her treats her patients with and
counsels, I before I began to understand
that, you know, I'm looking at these
mighty men. I'm wondering what what do I
got to do to to have this kind of skill?
What I got to do to have this kind of
discipline? What I got to do to
experience God's power in my life that
way? But I've got to be willing to go
back and look at, okay, well, what
happened? Where did I get, you know, off
track and what were the cognitive
distortions that came in and gave me a
wrong impression about myself, about the
world around me and other people and
even God, you know. So I think really
what a powerful story God gave us in the
gave you in the beginning of that book
if we sit and meditate on it. There's a
lot there.
>> Yeah.
>> Amen.
>> I like what you said Terry in in the in
the fact that like
all of us have different
callings or different armor.
>> What might be my armor might not be
somebody else's armor,
>> right? Um,
this wasn't a knock on Saul's armor, by
the way. It was just David was like,
"Well,
>> I'm not used to fighting
>> the way that you fight,
>> right? I'm not used to the armor that
you wear, so I'm going to
>> stick with what I know with how the Lord
has worked with me." And so I think one
of the first things we need to
understand in battle is God is going to
teach each one of us um how to fight in
a different in a different way.
>> Um I will bring it up again in those
>> God is a creative God. He's like he has
>> just think of all the
>> how many people have he has been created
or born or lived and whatever. So he's
like he makes it um I don't want to say
entertaining for himself but he's like
you're all different.
>> Yeah. So, I have to work with you all
differently and you're all gonna have a
different strength and provide a
different influence in the world as
well.
>> So, um in some of the old
>> kung fu movies that I used to watch, you
would sometimes you have like one master
training,
>> you know, some of you may know what I'm
talking about. Five different people
with five different styles,
>> right? So, there was
>> And you can accomplish the same thing
five different ways. Is that what you're
saying? it. No, it was just that he
taught them that that they would have
like there was a there was a snake
style, there was a toad style.
>> That's what I'm saying. It's a different
style, but you're going to get the same
you're going to get the same result.
>> The whole idea is to win, right?
>> That's what I mean. And
>> Teenage Mutant Ninja Turtles.
>> Teenage Mutant Ninja Turtles. Everybody
has a different Everybody has a
different power, right? Everybody has a
different skill, a different
>> focus, a different not focus, but a
different um Yeah. the different focus,
a different emphasis
>> in their battles. So the the way that
God teaches me how to fight may be
different from the way that God teaches
you how to fight,
>> right?
>> Um you know, but the whole issue, the
whole the whole idea is remembering that
God
>> has an armor.
>> Like God's armor isn't one sizefits-all,
>> right? He's going to tailor
>> tailor your ar your armor to you. Mhm.
>> He's going to tailor your fight to you
because every one of us has a different
battle, right?
>> None of us have the same exact fight.
>> And I love that about God. He
understands how different we all are.
The way he communicates to you is
different than the way he communicates
to me. He still telling me truth and
telling you truth and you telling you to
do the right thing and me to do the
right thing, but he knows I'm different
and you're different. So he has to talk
or communicate in a different way, you
know. So he's teaching me how to fight
in a different way
>> than he's going to teach you how to
fight. I just love that he's a personal
God. He personalizes
>> Amen.
>> U the way that he interacts with us.
Even the way that he gives us victory.
>> Yeah. Y
>> he's going to give us all he can give us
all victory just might look a little
different.
>> Y
>> I think that's beautiful. Amen. And that
you know why that is? I'm just because
he he we he wants us to have a personal
relationship with him.
>> So it has to be personal. He's the same
God. He doesn't change. But he allows
himself to be a little different for
each of us so that we can So it's
personal. The way me and God are are
just the way me and God are. Yeah.
>> And it's personal.
>> Yeah. So, if you think about that, like
the
there's a reason why Saul would never go
into a battle using stones
>> because that was David's.
>> Cuz that Yeah. He didn't grow up He
didn't grow up fighting with stones.
>> Right. Right.
>> But that was David's. Yeah.
>> David is out as a shepherd,
>> you know, and he's got his sling to to
protect his sheep,
>> to protect the flock. Mhm.
>> So, every one of us in the way that
we've been brought up in the Lord
>> and the the context in which we've been
brought up in the Lord, we have
different weapons,
>> right?
>> And
God can make a weapon out of anything,
>> right?
>> Stones, David, you're going to use
stones.
>> Again,
some of these movies, you got people
fighting with chopsticks.
>> Chopsticks. How are you fighting with
chopsticks? Right.
>> Right.
>> You have people fighting with all kinds
of like, how did you get that? How did
you make that a weapon? How did you make
that a weapon?
>> So, in that same way, God
God
tailor makes your fighting style to you,
right? He tailor makes
>> the the armor so that the battles you
face that are unique to you, you're
going to have a unique way to overcome
that. And the issue now becomes, how do
I get in tune with my own armor?
>> The reason why David said, "I can't use
Saul's ar." It's not that Saul's armor
wasn't effective or efficient.
>> If David had been trained with the
sword,
>> he would have, you know, I mean,
>> he used the sword afterward.
>> He was like, "All right, now that you're
down, let me let me take the sword." And
and I take your sword, by the way.
>> I love what Mooney said. God can use any
He can use anything. I don't want to I
can't go up for if you could scroll up
because I don't want to misquote her
because it was good. God wait no you
pastor. God can make a weapon out of
anything.
>> Okay.
>> I was just I just love that.
>> Yep.
>> Yeah. Terry, were you were you saying
something?
>> Creative. No.
>> No. I was just saying amen. I I you
know, pastor, when you started
mentioning the the sensei that taught
the five different guys,
>> I have been trying to get that picture
out of my head since you said it because
you took me straight back to kung fu
theater with that because it were these
five dudes and and and they would stack
on top of each other. It was crazy in
the movie how they come out and so one
had to be the foundation. He couldn't
think about himself as the top. He was
the foundation. Then the other would get
on his shoulder. the other would get on
his shoulder and they would stand tall
and they would fight like that. I it
didn't make sense. But together they
were awesome. But
>> they're flying through the air. But I
think that's so cool because you know
when you say, "Okay, Terry, you learn to
identify what your strengths are, what
your weaknesses are, what your gifts
are, and what God has given you." And in
the hands of God, they're awesome. But
for me, I keep going back and I know
with with the with the awesome ministry
you have, pastor, sometimes we come in,
I think we're thinking, "What's pastor
gonna say new this week? What's he gonna
say new this week?" I promise you this
week, you know where I've I've been?
>> Surrender.
>> I haven't ever been able to get past
that. And God has been reminding me,
Terry, that's all I've been trying to
get you to do
>> is surrender.
>> And when you do,
>> you'll see my power work.
>> Yeah. Yeah.
>> Amen.
>> I gotta I gotta throw this in here. Uh
Jason Diggs just said, "Jawbones,
lanterns, marching
>> voices have all been employed in
victories for faith."
>> That's powerful.
>> That's powerful. Imagine doing a study
and just going through all the things
that have been used.
uh all the weapons that have been used
that are unconventional weapons,
>> who uses a jawbone.
>> Yeah.
>> Who uses a jawbone for victory?
>> Right. So,
>> how is marching around a city seven
times?
>> That's right. Marching.
>> Giving somebody victory.
>> How is prayer a weapon?
>> Wow. Yes.
That's that to me that's well I know he
he can use anything but that's prayer is
a very strong Yeah.
>> strong weapon.
>> Yeah.
>> Very strong.
>> Amen.
>> So
let's go ahead guys and let's jump into
unless I don't know if anyone else had
had anything else to add to this
section.
>> If not let's start to jump into the
characteristics
of these mighty men.
And um I we'll take these
characteristics one by one.
And uh let me just read a section here.
So this is the first character
characteristic is purpose.
So it says um and these are the number
this is 1 Chronicles 12 verse 23. And
these are the number of the bands that
were ready armed to war and came to
David to Hebron to turn the kingdom of
Saul to him according to the word of the
Lord.
>> Goes on to say these mighty men of war
had had one united purpose. It was to
turn the kingdom of Saul to David
according to the word of the Lord. Where
there is no purpose, where there is no
mission.
Um, where there is no purpose, there is
no mission and no reason to fight.
>> Our mission as holy warriors is the
conquering of our own hearts, a turning
of our hearts from the kingdom of
darkness to that of light. The warrior
without a cause ceases to war with
passion to win. Let's talk about that
>> really quick before we go there. There's
a comment because this is Sabbath
school. Um, I the name went up so I'm
not I can't see who said it, but they
said, "How was the cross a weapon?"
[Music]
>> I think because it's the epitome of
surrender.
>> That's surrender. That's why I think
it's that's why the cross was a weapon.
>> Amen.
>> Because Jesus completely surrendered
>> the c You know what? This is what we're
going to do. Y'all just put in the chat
every weapon you could think of that was
ever used in the Bible.
>> And we're we're going to continue
talking, but I mean, y'all are already
like the jawbone, the cross,
>> the prayer. We know about the the you
know what we typically think of as the
the the armor of God, the helmet of
salvation. So, we know those, but I want
you to like try to think of every unique
thing, the stones.
>> Think of every unique thing that you
could think of. Put it in the chat. All
right. So, purpose. Why is it important
to have purpose in our
in the fight the Christian art of war?
>> Yeah.
>> And I open it up to the to the panels.
Frogs.
>> Keith. Yep.
>> Okay. Panels open or floors open. Why is
it important? What does purpose speak
to?
I've always seen it as
the purpose is to be like Christ, right?
>> And only when
Christ sees himself in us is when he's
going to return. So if that's not the
purpose, then what is? So
how how how
do you get there? For me, I've always
put it in my mind. Okay. Well, Cash, how
are you how how are you going to defeat
the things that God has made aware in
your heart? First of all, we all know
it's surrender. We can't move forward
unless we surrender everything first.
That's why the altar of sacrifice is
first, right?
So
the way that I've developed it in my
life through the guiding of the Holy
Spirit is okay, I would literally
picture my day
before I leave home, I have to be
covered by the Holy Spirit through
prayer and devotion.
And then if I want to be like Christ, I
have to purpose in my heart that
whatever situation I get into, whoever I
meet, whatever it is, I have to purpose
in my heart to give it to God as quickly
as possible so that he can put the
knowledge that I've read into the action
through my heart. And you always want
Christ in your heart in every situation
so that you can react a particular way.
So you could speak a certain way so that
even if you're not saying anything, your
your gestures, your your your
facial expressions, people are watching.
So you always want to be expressing
Christ. So that's how I've
put it for myself. And you know, it's
it's it takes practice and it takes a
while, but the Holy Spirit does do it
for you and it's it's been working.
>> Amen.
>> I I love all of these. Um, as you were
speaking, Kashie, people are putting in
weapons in the chat that they are
finding that God used.
Um
yeah, there's so many um
Moses's brought. Go ahead.
>> So yeah, I think that that's powerful,
Kashie. And I know like for me and I
think I don't know if Michaela was about
to say something or if that was Melinda,
but I'll just say this real quick. I
think um
you know understanding that
my
battle is to turn over this territory of
the heart
>> to the true king. Mhm.
>> um
helps you to put into perspective,
right? The same thing that motivated
those warriors to
uh understand that no, no, no,
this kingdom belongs to David.
>> Yeah.
>> You Satan, I mean Satan, Saul might be
ruling right now, but the kingdom
belongs to David, and we're backing
that. In that same way, think of
yourself as that that plot of territory
>> that Saul slash Satan,
>> the one who was anointed
>> but eventually fell away from God.
>> That God was no longer communicating
with him. That Satan is still trying to
have dominion and still trying to be the
rightful ruler over your kingdom.
And your fight is because you know now
this territory belongs to Jesus.
>> Yes. I love how interactive this this
Sabbath school is. It's not just our
guests. It's not us. It's it's all of
you
>> uh watching as well. There's so many
comments. You guys are are are put are
you're part of the study. I love it. I
love it. and you're just thinking of a
whole lot of weapons that we don't
really like um maybe we don't think
about sometimes but um you guys are
sharing you guys are sharing a lot. It's
great.
>> Amen. Amen. Um Michaela, was that you
about to speak or was that you Melinda?
I know it was one of you.
>> Yeah, it was me.
>> Okay.
>> Okay. Um,
so this idea of our purpose,
um, it's making me think back to like
chapter one where
what we're fighting for is principles of
our country, right? Which in this case
is
heaven, which is love and God's
character, God's true character. And so
like in the story of David,
then we're inspired by him. And it's
when we really see Jesus,
his sacrifice, the surrender, all of
that, his love inspires us. That's our
purpose. And
then as we're inspired by that, it
helps us fight ourselves. And we are
reflecting that love that those
principles that's our purpose and that's
how we fight that inspiration.
>> You're saying that love is the
inspiration.
>> Yeah,
>> that's good.
That's good because it was
>> the the definition I always like to go
to the definition of purpose, right? So
purpose is the reason for which
something is done or created or for
which something exists.
So why am I created? You know what is
the reason for which something is done?
Why am I doing this? What I've been
created for and why do I or why does
this thing exist? Once we can unpack
that then we can understand what purpose
is and why we operate and why we do the
things that we do. Why have that been
created? What's this? What is this uh
creating? Uh and what have I been
created for?
>> And why do I exist? Or why does this
thing exist?
>> Amen. Amen. Amen. Uh you know, uh
pastor, one of my favorite verses, uh
Revelation 4 11 says, "Thou are worthy,
O Lord, to receive glory and honor and
power, for thou hast created all things,
and for thy pleasure they are and were
created." And I love that because it
tells me I'm, you know, I'm created for
him and for whatever his will and desire
is for my life. That's what my purpose
is, you know. And but that's easy to
say, you know, for for me it took a
journey of life to come into
understanding purpose and it came in
phases for me. Uh my the the first thing
I realized is when God really touched my
heart with grace and forgave me and
allowed me to experience supernatural
peace through salvation. Um freely
you've been g given freely you receive
freely give. So obviously that that love
you want to tell everybody about Jesus
when you first fall in love with him.
You want to share that. But then as he
began to allow me to experience
deliverance from some of the things that
I had that held me chained and held kept
me in bondage, I I think I'm more like
that demoniac demoniac of uh Gatherine,
right? Uh he was in self-destructive and
cutting himself with stones and he was
in chains and no one could hold him or
no one could bound him. And then when
Jesus uh touched him and delivered him,
he's sitting at the feet of Jesus in his
right right mind. And he says, "You go
back to the capitalist, tell your family
and friends all the wonderful things
that God has done for you." So God had
given him purpose in his deliverance.
And like me, I realized, you know, I was
never meant to be in the streets. I was
never meant to be in pain. I was never
meant to be hurting myself and hurting
other people. I was never meant for I
was built for God and for love and to
share that love and to make that love
known to other people. Then one day I'm
sitting after I received present truth
and I be and and I begin to embrace the
Seventh Day Adventist message, the Bible
message, the true Bible message. I'm
sitting in this chapel one day and
there's a DVD praying playing and this
tall slim brother right with slight
Jamaican accent he's talking and he's
sharing this blueprint and he's breaking
that thing down of how through the ages
God has used different movements and
different churches and different um uh
spiritual leaders to do things and he
showed how the 7th day Adventist church
and our message falls right in I says
Lord look at this it is not a
coincidence that you brought me here
into this church and my purpose was even
deepened even farther. And so, and I
believe you said in that video, you
know, we're not we're not Seventh Day
Adventists by coincidence. You know,
this is part of God's plan.
>> And so, I seeing that, you know, so many
ways God deepens our purpose, you know,
but having that purpose keeps us rooted,
grounded, and on track and knowing, hey,
I was made for something. I was designed
for something. I was created for
something, and that's why I'm here, you
know, so I'm not tossed about so easily,
>> right? Amen. Amen.
>> Amen.
>> Um I know that we are
the conversation is good and we only
have just a few minutes left.
>> Yeah, we have about uh about five more
minutes.
>> I want to I want to just I don't know if
we should start this section,
but maybe we can end on this. I'm going
to read 1 Chronicles 12:33. This is
another characteristic
um of Zebulon such as went forth to
battle, expert in war with all
instruments of war. 50,000 which could
keep rank, they were not of double
heart. There is so much there
>> in terms of characteristics. But I just
want to talk about went forth just for a
second. Went forth.
>> In this verse, we find a few more
characteristics. The first is that they
were willing to go forth into battle.
>> These men had no fear. They were men who
believed in their mission and were
willing to put their lives on the line.
>> They were not civilians. They were
soldiers.
>> Um,
we too must be willing to go forth.
Though odds may be stacked against us.
Though our temptations seem as 800 in
number, we must go forward obtaining the
victory. Without the willingness to
advance, we can win no battle. So, the
reason I picked that number 800 is
because
>> I love it that they went I'm sorry. I'm
sorry and I interrupt you. I'm sorry.
>> But I love I just want to make this one
point. I just love that point like they
went forward with no fear.
>> Like God doesn't give us the spirit of
fear when we mentally
put our mind like I like David didn't
have any fear. He was so confident.
>> He had all the reason to be afraid.
>> He's big, David's little. M
>> he's stronger.
>> You have just a few rocks. You know what
I mean? It looks like he had all the
reasons to like look at a situation and
be afraid.
>> But he did not go into that. He was so
confident. And that's how we have to
approach
>> our enemy and our minds like as though
they had to have our mental game on like
all right God you gave me this weapon.
I'm going to fight and I'm not afraid
because you are my strength and you're
gonna beat the enemy. But go ahead.
>> Yeah. That's uh
>> how how did they get the courage? How
did they get the courage?
>> How how how how it was based on their
past victories.
>> Past victories.
>> Their past victories allow them to have
the courage to move forward to the
battle ahead.
>> So don't dismiss your past victories,
>> right?
>> Just that I'll leave it at that.
>> No, no, thank you, Lami. That's powerful
and that's true. You
>> can I quickly mention something?
>> The gohead. Yes. Go ahead. The resume
the resume got so
>> Yeah. Um yesterday in Friday Night
Lights um we were going through the
story of the man by the pool of right
>> and we were looking at other stories in
the past and we've seen how God has this
stopgo concept where with Balam I don't
know if I've um mentioned this before
but with Balam Bam was going somewhere
God stopped him in the road. Saul was
going somewhere Saul of Tarsus was going
somewhere God stopped him in the road.
Um, God stopped in the road when Zakius
was in the tree. God stopped when
Barardeameus was by the roadside. So God
has this concept of stopping either for
people or stopping people.
>> And yesterday we just noticed this thing
that the man by Bethada was told to go.
So, it seems like God tells some people
to stop when they're going the wrong
direction,
>> but others he tells go when they don't
know where to go. Yeah. And Michaela,
you should totally elaborate on this
because, you know, she was also part of
the discussion and I'm just I just can't
like this is so cool.
>> Melinda, what you did last week with the
mind blown like you're blowing my mind.
Michaela, I want to hear. Yes, please
continue on. and I want to hear more of
the discussion you guys had.
>> Okay. Well, it was also
he tends to tell people to go when
they're
stuck looking at something else other
than him.
And
>> Oh, yeah.
>> Yeah. But I think that really stood out
to me because like we looked at Peter
being called out onto the water to walk
to Jesus in the storm.
And if he'd stayed looking at Jesus and
kept going towards Jesus,
>> everything would have been perfectly
fine.
>> Mhm.
>> He would have conquered everything
around him really through Jesus. But
then he stopped and was looking at
separating house
>> and that's when he got stuck
>> and sank.
And I also want
>> Jesus came and pulled him up and pulled
him. Okay, let's go.
>> Yeah.
>> So, it was interesting.
>> I feel like it echoes really closely
with the parable of the um vineyard
workers where the master of the vineyard
goes out and all throughout the day is
like, "Oh, these workers are just
loitering in the marketplace." And then
he's like, "Well, what are you doing
here?" "Oh, we've got no work." "Well,
then come work in my vineyard." So this
master of the vineyard is always sending
these people somewhere.
>> And I don't know, I just think that the
idea that
if we don't stop God in the road, God
will stop us.
>> And if we are stopped looking at the
wrong thing,
>> he will send us somewhere right.
>> And he's trying to send us into battle.
>> Yeah. Exactly. Exactly.
>> That's where he's trying to send us.
>> Yes, man.
Ladies and gentlemen,
this has been a blessing. I I I feel
like we need to end it on their notes,
but man, I want almost want to see their
faces, but we were talking about this
last weekend, last week.
>> Um,
there's a whole lot of sermons, right?
And what both of the what both of them
shared. We're going to have a youth
>> young adult Sabbath soon.
Uh, we just talked about this and we
were talking about it with brother Terry
and sister Amber. Um,
>> and ladies, man,
>> one or both because I've seen tag team
sermons like y'all gonna be preaching
for Sabbath soon. So, keep that in
prayer. I just threw that out there
because that was so powerful.
>> I'm super nervous right now.
>> Well, yeah. Yeah. Don't be because you
were preaching right now. You've already
been preaching.
>> That's right. So yeah, that was very
powerful both of you guys. Thank you all
of you. What you have shared has been a
blessing. Unfortunately, because of our
tech delays, we don't we didn't have as
much time today, but that's okay because
nobody is rushing us. We're going to
pick up right here um for our when we
come back, we're going to pick up right
here because this was powerful, guys. I
love looking at all the different
weapons. I love
>> I'm gonna go through and collect
>> those weapons you put in.
>> Yes, you guys were like the chat. you
guys were on fire today just listing so
many
um yeah it was beautiful.
>> It was beautiful.
>> I'll just close with this thought that
uh you know it's uh something else to
think of little of uh David going out to
battle and he's just like he's so
confident because in his mind he knows
that God is standing behind him.
>> Yes. And that is how we have to think.
>> Yeah man. And we are out of time, but I
just have to say again, if we thought
that way, like guys, we can't allow
that picture to leave our minds, that's
how we
>> that's how the enemy wins. If we keep
that thought and that mental picture
that God is right here with me, he's
right here and he's fighting,
>> then we're not afraid and we don't get
discouraged.
>> Yeah. We just All right, God. I'm
walking by faith and your strength is
going to carry me through.
>> So,
>> Amen.
>> All right.
>> Thank you.
>> Thank all of our all of our
>> Thank you guys.
>> Sabbath school panel.
>> Okay. Well, thank you too. Thank you to
our viewing audience because you guys
have been putting good nice gems in the
chat and you've
>> Yeah, this was definitely Sabbath school
today. Praise God. We were all We were
having a study together. such a
blessing.
>> So I think we'll pick up on went forth
next week.
>> Yes,
>> we'll move into expert expert in war and
we're gonna actually I think we're going
to stay in this verse
um for a little bit. So because there
are several things in this verse that
we're going to be able to unpack and
talk about. So we'll pick up there next
week.
>> So again, for those of you that want to
get your own copy of Christian Art of
War, we're releasing uh chapters at a
time, but the first three chapters are
all on Mighty Network. So, please um at
the beginning of the divine worship, I'm
going to show you how to uh if you don't
have mighty network, how to get on, but
that's what you want to do because
that's where all the amazing things
happen here at Living Matt Church. So,
the first three chapters are there. So,
we want you to go on through this study
with us so that you guys can just uh be
a part of this program as we're going
through the Christian art of war. So,
with that said, let's close with prayer.
And I want you guys to stay tuned um and
continue to uh worship with us and go
into the divine worship. And please
invite a friend, a family member, share
this link on your social media.
>> Hey, Terry, could you close us out in
prayer?
>> Amen. Yes, sir.
Precious Father, Lord, thank you once
again for showing up in our midst and
manifesting your goodness, manifesting
your wisdom. Thank you for the way
you're moving in the members of LOCC,
Lord. Not just this panel, Lord, not
just our amazing pastor and first lady,
but Lord, through the membership in the
chat, Lord, uh your body is beautiful
and amazing and wonderful, God, and we
are so thankful as we rest in you. Thank
you for all the weapons of warfare you
have given us. They are mighty in you,
oh God, to the pulling down of
strongholds, casting down imaginations,
and every high thing that exalts itself
above the knowledge of you, oh Lord. We
give you praise, glory, and honor for
this wonderful time in Jesus name. Amen.
>> And we will see you in church.
[Music]
[Applause]
Heat. Heat.
Today, our travels have brought us here
to the beautiful country of Lebanon. And
here in South Lebanon, just north of the
Israeli Lebanese border, we find a
coastal town that takes us back into
time. It is here that we walk upon the
ruins of an ancient economic superpower
that once overlooked the majestic
Mediterranean Sea, a major Phoenician
seapport that goes back to before 2000
BC.
[Music]
The Phoenician city of Ty was once one
of the major crossroads of commerce and
commercialism in the ancient world. From
this harbor, the tyrants would send out
their merchant ships across the entire
then known world as far as western
Africa even up to northern Europe. This
famous city was known for their expert
craftsmanship of glassware, pottery,
textiles, tapestry and jewelry. They're
also known for harvesting the sea shells
from which they would extract and
manufacture the extremely rare and
expensive purple dye, the coveted color
of the kings, who paid an expensive
price to immerse the royal robes. Tyra
was once an ally with Israel during the
days of King Solomon, providing much of
the materials for the glorious sanctuary
in Jerusalem, a real blessing to the
people of God.
But this city became so rich and wealthy
that they soon became consumed with
pride and arrogance and the love of
ease. They began to waste their riches
on selfish ambition and sinful
indulgence. This kingdom who once
contributed to the beauty of the temple
and the glory of God now began to use
their power and their wisdom and their
riches to exalt themselves. They became
an icon of pride and arrogance. and
their spiritual fall was used as an
example of the fall of even Satan
himself. Using the king of Ty as a
symbol of Satan, the prophet Ezekiel
writes, "By your great wisdom and trade,
you have increased your riches, and your
heart is lifted up because of your
riches. You were perfect in your ways
from the day that you were created till
iniquity was found in you. Therefore, I
cast you as a profane thing out of the
mountain of God, and I destroy you, oh
covering cherub, from the midst of the
fiery stones.
[Music]
Because of his pride and arrogance,
Lucifer, that glorious angel, turned
himself into the devil and thus fell
from heaven. And his story is a chief
example of how pride goes before a fall.
And that which happened to him also
happened to this Phoenician kingdom that
followed his example. At the height of
her pride and power, the Bible says
concerning Ty. And they shall destroy
the walls of Ty and break down her
towers. I will also scrape her dust from
her and make her like the top of a rock.
They will lay your stones, your timber,
your soil in the midst of the water. It
shall be a place for the spreading of
nets in the midst of the sea. For I have
spoken, says the Lord God.
And just as the Lord predicted, the
prophecy came true. This ancient
economic epicenter was scraped to the
ground by mighty Nebuchadnezzar of
Babylon. And its rocky ruins were then
thrown into the sea by Alexander the
Great of Greece, creating a causeway
from the mainland to the island city.
And over the centuries, the causeway
have formed into a landmass that has
changed the geography of Tyra from an
island to a peninsula. And to this day,
it is used by modern fishermen for the
spreading of nets, just as the Bible
predicted thousands of years ago.
These ancient ruins of tire remain here
as a perpetual lesson to us that indeed
pride goes before a fall and that the
glory of the world is like the dust of
the wind here today but then blown into
obscurity tomorrow. Make no mistake
about it friends, power, wisdom, riches
and beauty are all gift from God. These
characteristics are to be used for the
glory of God and the blessing of others.
But once these things are used for
selfish exaltation and selfish gain,
that which was meant to be a blessing
quickly becomes a curse. And that which
was meant to be light quickly becomes
darkness.
My friend, each and every one of us has
been blessed with the same opportunity
that was given to ancient Ty. An
opportunity to use our time, our
talents, our resources to build up God's
kingdom. To make an investment that
brings eternal returns. to use our time
to impact all of eternity, to use our
gain to glorify God. But the enemy of
our souls is constantly enticing us to
follow his example of selfishness and
sin. He wants us to waste our substance
on earthly glory instead of spiritual
graces. He would cause us to believe
that pride is power and that meekness is
weakness. But the ruins of Ty testify to
the falsity of his lies.
But God promises that the humble in
spirit will retain honor. For God
resists the proud, but he gives grace to
the humble. You see, the nature of the
kingdom of God is very different from
the earthly kingdom of the tire. For in
God's kingdom, there's honor and
humility, beauty and simplicity, and
power and charity. And only as we come
down from our pedestal of pride and
self-sufficiency, will we then be
exalted in godly glory. For God said,
"If my people which are called by my
name shall humble themselves and pray
and seek my face and turn from their
wicked ways, then will I hear from
heaven, I will forgive their sins and I
will heal their land." Therefore, I
appeal to you today to never forget the
lessons that are learned from the
mistakes of this ancient city. Never
forget who is the true source of riches
and wisdom and beauty and power.
Therefore, humble yourself in the sight
of the Lord, and he shall lift you up.
[Music]
Hey, hey, hey.
Heat. Heat.
[Music]
Welcome back, Living Mana Church family.
We are so happy that you decided to
continue to worship with us today. And
if you're just joining the just joining
right now for the first time today,
please uh put in the chat where you are
worshiping from. We want to say a
special welcome to you. We are so happy
to have so many of you worshiping from
all around the world. It is such a
blessing to have all of you here with
us. And please before we get deep deeply
started here, please share this link in
your on your social media because we
want you to invite your your all of your
social media, but your friends and your
family uh to church today. It's so
simple to just put a link or just yeah
share this link on your social media um
or actually send this link to someone
that you want to come and worship with
you today. So, please put in the chat
where you're welcome, where you're where
you're welcoming from, where you're
worshiping from, and I will say a
welcome to you. And also put a one in
the chat if this is your first time
because I want to say a very special
welcome to you. All right, we have Jerry
here from San Diego. Jerry, it's always
good to see you. One of our uh original
church members here and works with our
kids for LMOC. Thank you for being with
us today. Blessings, joy, happy Sabbath.
Uh, good to see you from Barbados. MNA
from Tacoma, Washington. Welcome. Good
to see you here as well. It's just a
blessing to have so many of you here
worshiping with us. We are uh excited
about what how God is using this church
and we love having people an
international church from all around the
world. It is exciting. Uh, welcome
Evelyn Brown from Bermuda. Thank you for
being here with us at Living Mana
Church. want to say welcome and happy
Sabbath to Ivonne um and family from the
UK. Welcome to Living Mana Church and
Feliz Sabados to you too. Uh me I'm not
sure exactly where you are worshiping
from but happy Sabbath Fel Sabados to
you too as well. Jody, always good to
see you here. Um and from Vancouver
Island, one of our members and board
members of our church. Welcome as
always, Jod. Um, we have Don from
Oklahoma, OKC, Oklahoma City. Welcome.
Good to see you here. Keith from
Barbados. Good to see you here as well.
Um, just so many of you worshiping from
um around the world. So, it is okay. We
And welcome to And also welcome someone
from Trinidad and Tobago. Great to see
you here. Olivia from Edenberg, Texas. I
feel like I've just driven through
Edenburg on my way to somewhere in
Texas. Texas is so big. But welcome,
Olivia. Um, and Joseph from Wiser,
Idaho. Welcome Latonia from Lancaster,
California. Been there several times,
had family there uh for many years.
Welcome to Living Mana Church. Well,
welcome to everyone. We're so happy to
to see you here. Yes. Happy Sabbath to
everyone. Well, I was want to uh let you
guys know how you can stay connected to
Living Mana Church. One of the ways that
you can do that if you are here in North
America, you can receive a text. And if
you have not already done so, you're
going to want to sign up to be able to
get these text alerts. It allows you to
uh it reminds you, I should say, when
we're going live uh with live
programming. Uh it also has
announcements like how we had to switch
um our church link today because of
technical issues. Uh they were able to
send out a text alert to you to say,
"Hey, this is the new link, so please
join us here." And that's just one
example. Uh there's other things that we
communicate as well. So, it is really
helpful to get those text alerts because
you're thinking now like I will remember
throughout the week, but if you're like
me, you'll probably forget I have to
write things down or I h I have to write
it down or I'll forget. But we you can
write it down, but we're also here to
remind you as well. And that's by
getting those text alerts. And that's
only if you're here living in North
America internationally, which a lot of
our uh viewing audience and our
membership is around the world. that
won't work for you because you're not in
North America, but you can sign up for
Mighty Network and you can get a lot of
information from Mighty Networks. It's
really our it's our church hub, our
church home. Mighty Networks is our
virtual church home. That is where you
will learn so much about the small
groups that we have. You'll get to meet
different members and the leadership um
of different ministry that ministries
that are involved with Living Matter
Church. You actually form community
there. So, you're going to want to
download Mighty Network and that link
for you to download Mighty Network is in
the chat and that way you can stay
connected with Living Manage Church.
That way, if you are somewhere else in
the world besides North America and even
if you're in North America, you need to
sign up for Mighty Networks because even
our afterlow is on Mighty Networks now.
Our midweek prayer service soon will be
only on Mighty Networks and not on Altar
Live anymore. So, you're definitely
gonna want to sign up for Mighty
Networks.
Want to tell you guys that uh we also
have kids programming and that's
Locoscope
who is leading them is amazing. Uh our
kids are learning deep things in the
word of God and they're having fun while
doing that. So, if you want to get your
child signed up for LMOC Kids, you can
text the number there on your screen.
Um, and you can just te text kids to
that number. You can also send an email
uh to the um leaders of LMLC LMLC kids
and they will get back with you and help
you sign your kids up. All right. Want
to remind you guys that if you are
watching on power of the lamb YouTube,
we want you to go over to my living mana
and click subscribe and like um so that
we can grow that channel. So please go
over and do that um and just help us to
grow that channel so we can continue to
go into all the world and broadcast
God's love and the deep things of his
word to the to the the whole world. So,
if you would just go over to my living
mana and again click like and subscribe.
Want you to know that Pastor Meyers does
have virtual office hours and you can
schedule an appointment with him. You
can email Patrice at living manana.live
and she will be able to set that up for
you. And yeah, if you need to and this
is for our members. So, if you are
needing to speak to your pastor, please
email Patrice at living.live. live and
she will set that appointment up for
you. All right, we're excited to
announce that we have communion. We are
going to have communion on October 31st.
As you can see there, you can scan that
QR code if you are wanting to get the
link um to to be able to get the
supplies for the communion um the bread
and the um the wine, which is uh grape
juice. But it is if you need to get
those two things um you can you can scan
that code. It's also going to when you
scan that code, you're also going to see
how you can even make your own communion
bread um as well. But I believe that
information will also if you sign up to
get alerts um that information will
either get sent to you as well or we're
going to post it in Mighty Network. So
that's why it's so important to have
Mighty Networks and also to sign up for
the text alerts because you can get um
all of that information. Um it's pretty
easy to do that. It's more efficient. So
we're excited about communion on October
31st. So save the date and put it on
your calendar. All right. We are just
announcing that the hangouts, our very
first hangouts, which we are excited
for, is happening tomorrow, August 24th
at 6:30 p.m. So, you can get more
information there uh by scanning that QR
code and you can get more information,
but definitely put it on your your
calendar 6:30 p.m. tomorrow. So maybe
send give yourself a little a note or
alert. But I'm on that what's going to
happen is that the those who are signed
up for the text alerts or on mighty
networks, you're going to be reminded
you're going to be reminded that
tomorrow at 6:30 p.m. Central we are
having our first hangout meeting which
is uh excited exciting. So I'm excited
for that and to see all of you there.
It's going to be a lot of fun and it's
it's just what it is. We're getting to
know each other, hang out. There will be
um lots of um games and stuff like that.
But instead of hearing me say that, why
don't we just uh watch this video that's
going to tell you all about it.
[Music]
We want to see you all this
Sunday, August the 24th,
my time. That is 7:30 Eastern Standard
Time, 6:30 Central Standard Time. I just
I wanted to remind people
what Hangouts is. Hangouts is really
just hanging out. It's just sitting down
um in your living room like you're
visiting with friends and family. And um
we're going to, you know, do different
activities. We're going to have great
conversation.
Um you can bring some food, some chips
and guacamole if you want. And um
unfortunately, you can't share it with
us. You can eat it with us on screen. Um
so we'll be on Zooms. Um that is where
our meetings will be at. Again, we're
worshiping together, so let's hang out
together. And that is the goal. It's
about community, um, common unity,
conversation.
Um, you know, if you want to open up and
be transparent, if you don't and you
just want to, you know, be a part of the
conversation and just kind of sit back
and listen, that's okay, too.
Good morning,
L.
Praise the Lord. I am reaching out to
invite each and every one of you. You've
got to hang out with us this Sunday. We
are hanging. We are hanging. Get ready.
Get ready. Get ready. Get ready. This
Sunday, the 24th at 6:30 p.m. Central
Standard Time.
[Music]
>> Hello, Hangout.
This is Denise. I'm here to talk about
this coming Sunday.
This coming Sunday, we are going to be
going live in the hangout space. And
boy, do they have something great
planned for you guys. This is a church
that, you know, we know how to pray
together, right? So, guess what? We're
going to be playing together this
Sunday. You are invited. Every one of
you be there or one of my old sayings,
be square. Come and be part of the
hangout. love to see you. We're so
excited about this great new place and
space to get to know each other, hang
out, and just have some good
oldfashioned fun. See you then.
I'm excited. So, I hope you're excited.
I hope you're planning to attend. It is
going to be amazing. Thank you ladies
for putting that video together and for
all that you guys have done to put the
hangouts together. So, please, I want to
see you guys there tomorrow, 6:30 p.m.
Central time. It's going to be a lot of
fun. Just want to remind you guys that
um we after on September 1st, there will
be no more Alter Live. Yes, we are
moving over to completely to Mighty
Networks. And so uh please download
again mighty network so you will have
full access to our um everything that we
used to do um in altar live like the
Wednesday um the Wednesday service
prayer service will uh be on altar live
also um and of course our after our
afterlow for church is already there. So
just letting you guys know that
September 1st that is where we will be.
All right. So, we also want to just
remind you of the power line which and
that's exactly what it is. It's
powerful. Um and that is on uh YouTube.
It is uh the power line is a live chat
prayer chat service. So, people can come
bring their prayer request and they pray
for you live right there right then and
right there. Uh so, you can tell it's so
many people say, "Hey, my church will
pray for you." If you meet somebody who
says, "I need prayer." or you know
somebody who needs prayer, you can bring
their prayer request and you can bring
them so that they can just put in the
chat or you know what you can say I'll
put your prayer request in. You just
hear sit here and listen to people
praying for you because my church will
pray for you. But definitely you don't
want to forget about the power line.
That's 8:00 p.m. Central time. Um and
it's been such a blessing to so many
people. Um, and it's just a way for it's
it's it's powerful because prayer is
powerful, but it's also a way to
introduce people to Living Mana Church.
Just want to say another reminder about
Locosc Global. We are going global in
seven different languages. So, we just
praise God for that. And I just want to
show you what that looks like so that
you can if you know somebody who speaks
the language that uh we're about to
share or you can go and look at all the
different videos and the seven different
languages that we have available, you
can share with them the messages that
are there by Pastor Meyers in their
language. So just want to give you a
little peek at what that looks like.
[Music]
signific for
Fore
speech.
So again, please go to um Living Mana
Global on YouTube, check out the
different languages and the messages,
and if there's anyone that you know that
again speaks that language, please share
with them uh the messages in their
language. If you would like to support
Living Mana Global and Living Mana
Church, I'm just going to share with you
how you can do that. Please go to
Adventistgiving.org.
That is where you will be able to give
your tithe and your offering. Um there's
a virtual tithe envelope there. There's
a benevolence fund that you will see.
There's so many different things uh
there just like a regular tithe
envelope. And so you can give to all
those different areas. Your tithe goes
to support the Northeastern Conference
and the worldwide uh 7th Day Adventist
Church. And so we are very thankful to
be a part of that conference um here at
Living Mana. Your local church offering
that you give stays here with Living
Mana Church and it helps us to be able
to do all the many things uh that we do
um around the world with our ministry
and with our church. And so that is the
way that you can give virtually. If you
would like to mail in your tithe and
offering, you can use the address that
you see on the screen, PO Box 428, Owens
Crossroads, Alabama 35763.
And so those are the ways that you can
give. And we are just so thankful and we
want to say thank you to all of you who
support Living Mana Church who uh just
believe that God is coming soon and you
want to just you're so faithful to him
because you want um to see us to be able
to reach as many people as possible and
you you help us with that through your
prayers, through your financial gifts,
by sharing this church. uh like when I
asked you to share on your social media
about Living Manage Church that is
helping us to go into all of the world.
And so again, we thank you for all the
many things that you do to help and to
support Living Mana Church. I would like
to invite you now to pray with me as we
just offer up a prayer of thanksgiving
to God. If you please bow your heads
with me.
Heavenly Father, Lord, I just thank you
for your Sabbath, Lord. I thank you for
all of your your miracles and the things
that you do for all of us, Lord. Lord,
we all have been through we went through
another week and I know we met
challenges, but we also because of you
found victories, Lord. And we thank you
and we praise you for your faithfulness,
for your love, for your reminders that
just show us how much you love us and
how much you're there for us, Lord. So,
we praise you for that. Lord, I want to
lift up all of the people who are
watching. There's so many different
things that they could be going through,
Lord. So many things that have to do
with family. So, I ask that you will
intervene with for them on that. So many
are going through health issues. Please,
Lord, heal them. Many are going through
um issues with just raising children.
Please give them the strength and the
wisdom, Lord. the marriages. Help them
to figure out your way to have a happy
marriage, Lord, so that they can glorify
you in their marriage and just heal any
hurts and pains that are there, Lord.
People are going through financial
issues, Lord. Give them uh bless them,
work a miracle for them, Lord, and show
them how they could even manage their
money even better once you have blessed
them, Lord. Just just give them wisdom
in that area. And Lord, we're all
praying that you will take us into a
deeper walk with you. Lord, help us to
take a deeper dive into your word. Um
that that is so important that we have
to understand it for ourselves. Lord,
help us not to be so busy that we just
don't take that time to study your word
and to pray to you the way that we
should. Lord, I'm praying for Pastor
Myers that you will give him that you've
I you've given him the message, Lord,
but that he will deliver this message
and that we will re with a powerful way
that you want him to and we will
respond. Allow it to hit our hearts in
the way that you want it to, Lord. And
we ask all these things and Jesus name.
Amen.
[Music]
We are church. We are redeemed and
chosen trusting in the God of love, the
God of hope, the God of atonement.
We are church. We believe in one way,
one truth, one life. Devoted, eyes fixed
on the prize, devoted to Christ.
We are church. We put God first. We are
like-minded people created in Christ for
good works. Made in the image of
greatness. Made to reflect the greatest
love ever known.
We are church. The light in the dark.
The hope to the hopeless. A brand new
start. Peace for the broken heart. A
love that has open arms. We are church.
Not four walls. We are a body of
believers following the call. The call
to know we are forgiven. The call to
love without condition. The call to
trust without division.
We are church, a community with open
doors serving the poor, living for more.
We are broken people with a united cause
and unbroken love in a divided society
proclaiming Jesus is Lord.
This is what we do. We don't judge. We
don't hold a grudge. We are not perfect.
But we aspire to love.
We are church.
[Music]
You are
the
Are you hurting and broken within?
Overwhelmed
[Music]
by the weight of your sin,
Jesus is calling.
[Music]
Have you come to the end of yourself?
Do you thirst for a drink from the well?
Jesus is call.
Oh, come to
the altar.
The father's arms are open wide.
Forgiveness
was bought with
the precious blood of Jesus Christ.
[Music]
Yeah.
Leave behind your regrets and mistakes.
Come today. There's no reason to wait.
Jesus is calling.
Bring your sorrow.
Bring your sorrows and trade them for
joy.
From the ashes, a new life is born.
Jesus is calling.
Oh. Come to
the altar.
The father's arms are open wide.
Forgiveness
was born with the precious blood of
Jesus Christ. Oh, come to
the altar.
The father's arms are wide. forgiveness
was bought with
the precious blood of Jesus Christ.
[Music]
Oh, what a
pleas.
[Music]
Bow out before
him
for he is Lord of all. Sing hallelu.
Christ is rising
[Music]
[Applause]
hallelujah. Oh,
Christ is rising.
[Music]
[Applause]
Sing hallelujah.
Christ is risen.
[Music]
Bless your name.
Precious. Oh, precious is the throne
that makes me
>> That makes me white as snow.
Oh,
>> no others.
I know.
>> Nothing.
[Music]
Nothing but the blood of Jesus.
Oh, what a savior.
You
might go
sing hallelujah
[Music]
rising with
[Applause]
him
for he is
singing hallelujah.
Christ is
[Applause]
what a
wonderful
single
[Applause]
Christ is is there.
[Music]
>> We
for he is
singing hallelujah
Christ.
[Music]
>> Oh what a savior.
Even he wonderful.
Sing hallelujah.
Christ is risen.
[Music]
Bow down below.
>> Bow down before
him.
>> For he is.
[Music]
Sing hal hallelujah.
Christ is risk
[Music]
for
was with the precious blood of Jesus
Oh, come to
the altar.
The father's arms are open wide.
Forgiveness
was bought with
the precious blood of Jesus Christ.
[Music]
Here at Living Mana, we bear each
other's burdens. When you need support
or prayer, when you're feeling
discouraged
or alone or anxious,
you don't have to face life struggles
alone.
[Music]
Let us come boldly unto the throne of
grace that we may obtain mercy and find
grace to help in our time of need.
The Lord is close to the brokenhearted
and saves those who are crushed in
spirit.
[Music]
Greetings. Greetings saints of the most
high God and welcome to another edition
of living manners prayer and praise
time. I am brother Terry and by the
grace of God I am accompanied by my
lovely Brian Hammer today. So so
thankful to have you here with us
sweetheart and we are thankful to be uh
able to continue to serve you and to
love you and to fellowship with you and
to worship with you today. Uh love
y'all. Sister Marisella put in the chat
says, "Lord, we feel your presence." So
true, sister.
>> So true. We do.
>> It's so good to be here.
>> I know you guys have probably wanted an
update on my health journey. I've been
in and out of the hospital and the ER
for the last month and a half, but
praise God, I haven't been there for two
weeks, and I'm feeling a little better
this week. So I am here and grateful to
be here. If you could keep me in prayer.
So the latest I'm still having quite a
lot of kidney issues and infections and
I am going to be going to UC San
Francisco Medical Center. They're going
to take over my medical uh stuff. So
keep me in prayer that I can get those
appointments soon, get the surgery done
soon, and I can be on the road to full
recovery. So,
>> Amen. Amen. Amen. We're definitely
believing God for that, and we want to
thank God for you, the body of Christ,
you know, uh we don't want all attention
to be on us. We want attention to be on
Jesus. Exactly. But uh in whether it's
whether it's messy, whether it's
raggedy, whether it's blessed, whether
it looks victorious, where it looks
celebratory, whatever it looks like, we
want to be able to reflect the goodness
of God even when it hurts. Even when
there's tears and rejoicing, we want to
be able to love him and love you and
serve you. That's what we want to do. Uh
that's our purpose. God has given us
purpose. And uh
>> he is so good.
>> Amen.
>> What a good God we serve, right?
>> And look, look, let's gonna keep it
real. I don't want to sit here being all
uh polished and refined and composed and
give you some sterilized performance,
you know. I want to be real about it.
There have been days where I've had to
drive to work early in the morning
crying. There have been days nights
where I I don't really sleep because I'm
up, you know, checking making sure my my
bride is fine and, you know, listening
and wrestling with doubts and questions
and fears and the enemy. That's all a
part of it. That's all a part of the
sweet surrender of entering into this
peace. So, want to thank God for it. We
don't want to we don't want to pretend
about it. We want to keep it real. You
know, it's it's a struggle, but the
victory is ours. Can we say amen?
>> Absolutely.
>> Amen. Amen. And you know, I want I'm
going to do some special shout outs, but
I want to say this. You know, life looks
different through the eyes of
revelation.
Life looks different through the eyes of
revelation. Sister Tante, first lady had
a shirt on today says, "Where he guides,
he provides."
>> Amen. It's interesting because I'm
talking about revelation. It's right now
in the midst of the stuff we're going
through, the season in our life, God has
given us powerful revelation. He's used
pastors, pastor's messages, pastor's
book particularly. Get that book,
saints. Meditate on that book. Get that
book. And I'm telling you, God is doing
some powerful stuff. And and so I'm
thankful for it. I mean, you know, it
your situation don't have to change, but
when revelation comes, everything
changes. So, we got three men on the
cross. one dying in sin, one dying from
sin, one dying for sin. They're all in
the same situation. Revelation makes the
difference. Amen. And that's what's
happening with us right now. And we're
thankful to God uh that revelation has
come and it makes the trial bearable.
And you know, so we're we're thankful.
And so anyway, I wanted to shout out uh
blessing and Ayana, sister Marisella,
y'all in the chat. Y'all warettes are
just amazing. Love y'all. Sister Sheila
and the women's ministry and everybody
there. I can't even start with the
women. And Sister Annette Rivas, all of
you sisters, y'all do so much wonderful
work. And so we we really want to say
thank you. Majesca, we saw you in the
chat. You're the me who said uh Feliz
Savo. So definitely want to thank y'all
for doing all the wonderful work you do.
Sister Jackie, Sister Joanne, Sister
Pauline, just every the women of God at
LMOC are just on fire here. We're so
grateful for
>> love y'all. Sister Denise, we saw you on
that video. And sister Sister Angela,
you know, I shouldn't even say it.
>> Takara Takara who is coming off her
anesthesia.
>> I'm about to get to Takara.
See, that's why I don't want to start
because it's too many of y'all and y'all
just on fire. And but I look, Brother
Kashif, Pastor Loi, stand up and
represent. I want to give a special
shout out to Brother Elco leading the
men's ministry. Amen. Brother Elco, get
them fired up and recruit the men to to
stand up and and fill the ranks,
brother. So, we thank y'all. We love
y'all. One more special shout out I've
got to give today. It's in my heart if
y'all don't mind.
And that is to Sister Jerry Harvey
Leonard from San Diego, our girl. These
spiritual cookies that she' been giving
us to comfort our hearts. I mean, Jerry,
thank you, Jerry, for always being there
and always being encouraging, always
checking in on us, loving us. We love
you, Jerry. Jerry, thank you. And the
wonderful work you're doing with with
the children, you and and and Lawrence
and PJ and Coach and Tanya, y'all are
y'all on fire. So, thank y'all so much.
And we get to see the fruit of it right
here. Y'all have see some big fruit
coming here when the when the teens and
youth do uh the entire Sabbath service.
So y'all get we we'll be in touch with
y'all about all that. So anyway, love
y'all. Love y'all. Love y'all. Want to
welcome Sister Dolores. Uh uh Mama
Dolores. This is Shaunine's mom is our
newest LMOC prayer warrior. Welcome,
Sister Dolores. We got to get together.
We got to get together, do some
fellowship, some praying. You know, your
daughter already keeps me on the phone
like three and four hours at a time. I
don't know how you going to get a word
in, but we got to get a chance to talk.
Sister Dolores, love you and looking
forward to having you laboring with us
and I hope I'm not leaving anything out.
Power Wednesday and the power line. This
week's power line is going to be manned
by none other than our own brother Ross
and Sister Gina Brower. Come on out and
and support us. But first, stop by Power
Wednesdays midweek prayer service. I
want to give a shout out to all the
living men of membership and prayer
warriors. Man, there's strong. The
numbers are up high. They're praying.
They're on fire. Please know that all
your labors in the Lord are are are are
just uh beneficial to the kingdom of God
and making a difference in the lives of
so many people. Please don't think your
prayers are not making a difference. I
love what sister Tante said this
morning. Our first lady when y'all were
listing all the different weapons and
she mentioned Yeah. Prayer. Prayer.
Prayer is the weapon. God has given us a
powerful weapon. One of the most
powerful weapons. So pray y'all pray.
Amen. I see y'all in the chat. welcoming
Mama Dolores. Mama Dolores, we want to
welcome you again and we thank God for
you. Please come on in. Come on in. And
y'all remember, share the mana. Share
the mana wherever you go and everything
you do. Ah, there's no way I'm going to
forget this one. Sister Zadwa Malingo,
your your birthday's tomorrow. And so,
happy birthday to you, our beloved
sister.
>> Yeah. you said you were feeling drained
or something, but we're praying for you
that the Lord will strengthen you with
might by his spirit that he will quicken
your mortal body by his spirit in you
and just help you figure out a way to
get a hold of some some that boost of
energy you need. But uh wow, happy
birthday to you. So,
so amen, sister. Praise God for another
year of life. So, my love, how about
some praise reports?
>> That was quite the roll call, wasn't it?
How about some good news then?
>> All right,
>> I'm excited for our praise reports this
week. Before I do that, just a reminder,
if you have a prayer request or a praise
report that you would like to submit or
you would like to join the prayer team
or a special ops prayer team under the
prayer team umbrella, we're always
looking for people to join us. Please
send an email to pray
livingmana.urch.
If you need to request a special ops
team for yourself or a loved one, please
send an email to spec ops. That's spcops
livingmana.urch.
If you would like to join the women's
ministry, please send an email to women
livingmana.urch.
And if you would like to join the men's
ministry, please send an email to
sevenloaves. That's s eve ven l o a ves
at living manana.urch.
All right. To start us off,
Matina Whitehead. Listen,
>> Tina has been
so patient.
>> Extremely patient.
>> Extremely patient. She's asked me to
read her prayer request or her praise
report. I'm so sorry, praise report. And
I was gone sick and so she has been
waiting. So, here we go. In June, I
requested prayer for a positive outcome
as a result of my insurance company's
payment denial for treatment received by
a specialist in the amount of $2,900.
After getting upset and being angry, I
asked God what to do. In a quiet
response, he told me to make a phone
call to a particular government agency.
I did. Holding my breath, I told them my
story. I didn't hear anything until the
end of July. Medicare stepped in and
paid the expense except $62.
Praise God. Thank you, Jesus. I want to
confess that I'm not proud of my
reaction to the situation. This was a
test of faith. I failed it and was
reminded that these tests come to
straighten us, that we need to trust God
for deliverance, both big and small.
Many times we believe we are ready for
translation.
My reaction makes me realize that I need
to take heed less I fall. Thank you for
your prayers and support.
>> Wow. from $2,900
to 62.
>> God is good.
>> Hallelujah. Amen.
>> God is good. Next one coming from Ineta
Carr. The doctors told me my bone marrow
was not producing good cells. And to
make a long testimony short, they said
it's now working. So I praise God for
the prayers and miracles in my
situations.
Praise God. from Takara Dorsia. I want
to thank all of my prayer warriors team
and our special ops for praying for me
and over me during my surgery. I know
that the Lord was in the room when when
they put me under.
And I just got to say this
to Cara.
I saw her on social media on her way to
get this oral surgery done and she could
not have looked more dressed up and diva
out for this surgery. Girl look good for
this surgery.
>> We're talking about Sister Jakar, right?
>> Yeah. She she came walking in for that
surgery looking like a queen.
>> Hallelujah.
>> All right. Next from Vivian Shelton.
Thanks for praying for my son, Hobart
Shelton. He was burned eight weeks ago.
His feet are healed now and he is back
at work. I thank God for his healing and
thanks again for praying for him. From
Monica Garin, thank you Locosc for your
prayers. My husband's knee replacement
surgery on Wednesday went well and he is
on the steady road to recovery and
healing.
>> Amen. He was able to walk outside this
morning with our dogs, especially my
service dog, eagerly watching over him
to make sure he was okay, too. Please
continue to pray for him, for our family
and strength for me to keep up, most of
all for our family's salvation. See you
while at church
from MPG, which
I think is Monica Garin,
I believe. MPG.
Um, she also said, "Thank you, Lord, for
protecting my daughter and protecting
students when two buses from her school
each had accidents within an hour of
each other. In both instances, all were
safe. God is so good." From Olivia
Torres. God works in miraculous ways. I
am processing a new tenant for my vacant
unit and in God's perfect timing. He is
always coming through. Thank you for
your prayers. God is good all the time.
>> All the time. Amen.
>> From Barbara Simmons. Thank you, Jesus.
You are a powerful and wonderful God.
Hurricane Erin is now just north of our
island of Anguila. Praise God. Had it
been just a little south, we would have
had a direct hit.
>> We are having tropical storm winds and
some rain, which we really need. Our God
is so powerful. Even in the wind and
waves, they obey him. To God be the
glory.
>> Yes. from Jesse Fostino.
Grateful for norwalls and unicorns.
Full of gratitude for not having work
for six weeks. I've had time with my
family. Praise the Lord. From Denise
Richardson, praise report. Thanking God
for a good health report yesterday.
>> Amen.
>> Two more from Pauline Goody. I went to
urgent care yesterday
after we harassed her that morning.
It is a sinus infection and my blood
pressure was up. My oxygen was low and I
had a headache. I went back home and
continued steaming with eucalyptus oil,
taking my cough medicine, drinking
plenty of water, and I took a colon
cleanser. I'm feeling so much better. I
praise our Lord and Savior Jesus Christ
in the prayers of the family. Thank you
all. much love. And then she sent
another praise report and a prayer. I
went to work last night because God
wanted me to witness to a 20-year-old
young man named Raheem at the shelter.
He believes in God, but having a hard
time with negative thoughts that Satan
had put in his head. We talked
throughout the night. I told him to give
Jesus and counseling a try. Then the
Holy Spirit told me to tell him the
story of how sin came into the world.
When I tell you that this young man sat
up straight and listened,
>> I saw what the Holy Spirit was telling
him was connecting. I saw the hunger he
had for God. It was beautiful. We got on
the subject of what happens when we die.
So, you already know. I told him to
listen to Heaven's Diary.
I have to work Sunday morning and I told
him we can discuss Heaven's Diary then.
Please keep Raheem in prayer as Jesus
brings another precious soul to the
family of God. Hallelujah. Praise the
Lord. Thank you, Jesus.
>> Amen.
>> And finally, from Nicole Curtis,
>> prayer warriors, thank you so much for
praying for my friend Sonia. She has
been searching for a job that meets her
financial needs for close to two years.
Her latest round of interviews with this
company seemed to go well, but this has
happened before time and again. Well,
this time she got the job. She let me
know on Friday that she has accepted the
position. Praise God.
>> Amen.
>> Saints, we have to keep pressing on even
when the answers to our prayers seemed
delayed. Thank you again, prayer
warriors.
>> Hallelujah. Come on, saints, and give
God some praise.
>> Amen. Amen. See, see all them all them
answers to prayers. Some of y'all are
getting ready to doze off. See, you get
just because we're we're not here or
others are not here. God doesn't stop
doing what he does. God gonna keep right
on blessing. You know, the enemy got to
get his lies out there. You know, all
the bad news, but God's got good news.
Amen.
>> Good news, good news. He is working. He
is God. And he is on the throne. Want to
thank y'all. I see some of you in the
chat. Sister um Nicole, we love you.
Sister Takara, we saw you. You said,
"But God." I had that shirt on earlier,
a t-shirt. But God. So, we love y'all.
Love you. Sister Ashley Owens,
you're going to be doing your
orientation this week. And then we're
going to have a special welcome for you.
We need to do something special. Sister
Ashley, let me tell you what a wonderful
prayer warrior and wonderful mother and
and I'm and wife and just doing a great
job. We're gonna we're blessed and
honored to have you join the ranks of
the living man of prayer warriors.
Sister Ashley. Hallelujah. So,
>> we're getting ready to go to the throne
of grace, saints of the most high God. I
want to read off some of these prayer uh
uh requests today that we got in the
chat. If we did not if I didn't read all
of you don't hear me read yours, it
doesn't mean that um we are not catching
it. Our prayer words in the chat are
very vigilant and watchful and they're
gathering them up. and sister Pauline
whose praise report we read her and
sister Christina are always diligent and
always about uh collecting all the
prayer requests not just here but from
also the from the power line from the
emails uh from wherever you send them in
we get them and they compile them into
list and disseminate them amongst all
the prayer warriors so we're always
praying by the grace of God and we feel
called and led and privileged to be able
to do that so keep on keeping on saints
and Don't forget to let us know what
happens.
>> Amen.
>> Uh when your prayer requests uh come
through.
So um we want to lift up all the prayer
requests in the Living Man of Prayer
Warriors prayer request chat from top to
bottom. Every prayer request that has
ever come in, we're going to continue to
lift that up before the Lord. Three
Angels Messages is asking us to pray for
her as she decides to move back to
Jamaica. So we're praying about that.
Laya and Wes, we're continuing to pray
about your move to Idaho. Sister Matina,
your son David is graduating from the
police academy and going to be doing job
interviews. So, we're praying that he
will be placed in the place where he can
do the most good and God protect and use
him. Definitely a minister of God in
Jesus name. So, and LOCC, we want to
pray for the LOC teams, LMLC kids, want
to pray for the leaders of the ministry,
uh, Sister Tanya, Sister Jerry, Coach,
uh, PJ Lawrence, all of y'all continue
to do the wonderful job that you're
doing. Living Mana Online School of
Evangelism, I'm telling you, saints,
what an awesome, awesome vision and
movement God has started. Want to pray
for all of our staff, all of our
students. Want to pray for our
administrators. Uh, Sister Michelle
Watson Grant and Sister Jodie Mccclure
Liquor here. What a blessing. And we
want to pray about the ministries that's
going to come out of that. That's a big
deal. I'm that is a big deal. A church
and a school and ministry just coming
out of that's a modern day school of the
prophets. So, we're praying about that.
I want to pray for Taj and his bride and
Revelation of Hope, Reflections of Hope
Ministries that they continue to uh be
fruitful and abound. Um want to pray for
Bev. Bev wed. You uh said that you've
been going through spiritual warfare and
the devil has been telling you that you
don't have purpose. You already know
that's a lie, okay? Because God has
already said he has a purpose for your
life in his word. So we were praying for
you that you will continue to stand up.
We thank God that the word on purpose
today from pastor's book was a blessing
to you. We're praying, praying, sister,
praying for you. Um, Terresa Faulk,
we're praying for your husband and
mother that they will come to the Lord
Jesus. Pastor Low, Melinda, Michaela
Kashie, praying for y'all who sit on the
board on the panel uh uh for Sabbath
school. Wonderful stuff. Thank y'all so
much for joining us. Michelle Kendrick,
we're praying for your son-in-law, Alex.
Uh he's been a pagan, but now he's
listening to sermons. Amen. And so, we
want to thank God for that. that once
that incorruptible, the incorruptable
seed of God's word gets in his heart,
it's going to bring forth a harvest. So,
we're praying about that, we'll keep it
watered with prayer. Sister Zadwa, we're
praying for you that you will find
energy and some strength in your body.
And again, happy birthday, brother
Artell. Praying for brother uh
Moananiel, praying for his health and
his walk with the Lord. He's there in
Atlanta. Uh we're praying that um God
will just bless him in his heavenly spir
in his spiritual walk and his physical
walk. Um, we want to pray for Hangouts,
who's having a meeting tomorrow at 6:30.
Uh, uh, I think that's Eastern Standard
Time, Central.
>> Central time.
>> So, Hangouts, we'll be praying for y'all
that that would go well. Uh, I believe
me and Emma will be dropping by, pray
with y'all. And as Sister Denise said,
we know how to pray together. We need to
know how to play together. Okay.
Exactly. Sister Denise, come to us
tomorrow.
>> Amen. Okay. And Sister Crystal, love
you, Sister Crystal. Uh we'll be praying
for you that your job hours will be
changed so that you'll be able to be
home with Scarlet and Kayla. And we're
praying also that your grades will
reflect your desire to earn the degree
that you're working towards. So thank
God for that. Um
also, Sister Jodie Mccclure, our own
beloved Sister Jod Mcclair has remind us
that uh we would uh pray that everyone
who watches LMOC on social media will be
encouraged to join us. We're also
praying about human trafficking and that
um those involved in human traffick have
gotten caught up and that will be
protected and rescued that God will step
in and make a difference. She's praying
reminding us to also pray for revival
and reformation amongst God's people.
So, we're definitely keeping that lifted
up. And I want to just I want to pray
this prayer request came from our
beloved sister Marisella Johnson. Sister
Marisella, thank you. You are such a
special gift to LOC. We hear your heart.
We hear your conviction in your prayers.
We're praying that God will bless you in
every way, my sister, that he would just
continue to put his hands on your life
and bless you. You put a prayer request
in for me and Amra that the Lord would
refresh our spirit
>> and that he would allow us to experience
the joy and peace that can only come
from him. I want to tell you God has
already began to answer that prayer,
Sister Miraella, in the middle of it.
This don't make no sense.
>> I'm telling you, when revelation comes,
yes, nothing about your circumstances
have changed, but you know that you know
that you know God is moving. And that's
where we're at. And we want to thank God
in spite of it. We thank God. And and
and I still am tickled when I think
about what Sister Jerry said,
>> you know, uh
hallelujah,
Jerry. Oh my lord.
I see a prayer request from Annie
Mitchell
asking to allow her body to produce more
bone marrow.
>> Yes.
>> And to bring forth full healing and
restoration.
>> Thank you my love for catching that. We
are definitely be praying for that.
Sister Elder Robert E. Plant, we love
you. So glad you have joined us. We're
definitely praying for you and your
family. Lord, continue to bless you and
allow you to continue to be a blessing
to all of us. Sister Lanson Landre, we
see you there. Prayer for rest and job
interviews soon. Amen. Sister Landre,
you're one of our own prayer warriors.
There are over 300 watching right now.
If you have not put a prayer request in
the chat, but there's a prayer request
in your heart. Every one of you
watching, we're lifting you to the
throne of grace right now as we go
before our Lord. And so God, we thank
you, Father, that as we come before the
throne of grace right now, we thank you
for the blood of Jesus that has
purchased us, that's made us sons and
daughters of God that has given us right
and access into your presence. Lord, we
confess our sin before you right now in
Jesus name. Wash us, cleanse us, Lord,
restore us to perfect fellowship with
you. Blot out our iniquities from the
record in heaven. Oh God, as we stand
before you as yours, Lord, as you are
teaching us to surrender to you.
Surrender, Lord. The world has taught us
that surrender means weakness. Surrender
is where the war is over. No, surrender
is where the war begins. Because when we
surrender to you, that is where our
power and strength ends and yours
begins. And the enemy cannot stand
against you. And so we surrender to you
right now, Lord, in the name of Jesus.
We give you the glory, the honor, and
the praise. Thank you for the revelatory
word that comes to us in the midst of
our trial. That comes to us in the midst
of our confusion. That comes to us in
the midst of our pain. Comes to us in
the midst of our doubt, comes to us in
the midst of our worry, comes to us when
we're crying, Lord. Comes to us when
we're ready to give up and give in.
Thank you for the revelatory word that
saves us, the living word of the living
God. Thank you, Father, that when you
bring us to our wits end, that's where
your glory begins. That's where the
victory begins. Lord, when we stop
negotiating, when we stop trying to
manage the situation, when we stop
coming before you with polished prayers,
when we stop coming before you all
composed and well put together and just
quoting scriptures to stuff our pain,
but we bring our pain and lay it before
you. We bring our hurt and lay it before
you and trust in you and believe in you,
Lord. Thank you, God, for leading us
into battle. As the pastor said this
morning, thank you for leading us to
war, Lord God, where we learn to
surrender and let God be God. Thank you
that you are greater than all of these
things that we've lived before you
today. You're greater than these
sicknesses and diseases. You're greater
than the unbelief. You're greater than
that rebellious son and daughters uh
rebellion against their parents. You're
greater than those uh spirits of
darkness and blind and deaf spirits,
dumb and deaf spirits that keep your
people from coming and calling upon you,
that keep your folk from hearing the
voice of the living God. You are
greater, Lord. And so let your love,
Lord, shatter the walls around the
hearts and the you pull the walls of
Jericho down. Hallelujah, Lord. And
we're shouting today in Jesus' name.
Hallelujah, God. That the walls around
the hearts of our loved ones will come
down. all walls around their minds will
be pulled down in the mighty and
majestic name of Jesus Christ of
Nazareth, your son, our Lord and King,
Lord. And we thank you today that you've
heard every one of these prayer
requests. Not one has escaped your
notice. Thank you, Jesus, that you're
more than able. Thank you that you're
our conqueror from Calvary. Thank you
that you're a fairest among 10,000.
Thank you that you're the lion of the
tribe of Judah, a friend that stickketh
closer than a brother, a rock in a weary
land, our refuge, our strength, our
strong tower, our seating and great
reward. Thank you, Jesus. Hallelujah.
That you're more than enough. More than
enough, God. And we give you all of the
glory, all of the honor, and all the
praise. Send your miracle working power
on our behalf, Lord God. And sometimes
that we know that the miracle is not
that our circumstances have changed, but
the miracle is that we can obey you, oh
Lord, and worship you and rejoice in you
even in the middle of our storm. That we
can claim the victory, Lord. And we give
you glory for that today. We give you
honor and praise, Lord. May the world
look upon our faith. Look upon your
glory upon us as you promised in Isaiah,
Lord. That the the glory of the Lord
shall rise upon thee, Lord. And that
kings shall come to the brightness of
our rising, Lord God. That that nations
will come, Lord. That folk will come and
cleave to us and what is this that you
have that I don't have, that the world
doesn't have? What is it that you got?
May we lead them to you, Lord, in Jesus
glory and wonderful name. For you said,
Lord God, they that turn many to
righteousness shall be as the stars of
the firmament. Lord, let it be according
to your word. All God's people declare.
>> Amen.
I
will
lift up my eyes to the heels.
From whence cometh my help.
My help cometh from
the Lord.
The Lord which made heaven and earth.
[Music]
He
said
he will not suffer thy foot
thy foot to be moved.
The Lord which keep
[Music]
not slumber
sleep
[Music]
for
the
Lord is thy keeper.
The Lord is thy shame
[Music]
upon
thy
right hand.
Upon
thy right hand.
No,
the sun shall not smite thee by day. of
the moon by night.
He shall preserve
the soul
even forever
more.
My
help.
[Applause]
My help.
All of my help cometh from
the
Lord.
[Music]
Heat. Heat.
[Applause]
[Music]
Heat.
Heat
up here.
[Music]
Heat.
Amen. Welcome uh church family. I want
to wish you all a happy Sabbath and um
we are going to get into the word of
God. Um, immediately this morning, we
got a very special message and um I I
pray that the title of this message will
forever
be
uh written in your minds. Um, by God's
grace, this is going to be a
revolutionary
message. I want you to go ahead and hit
that like button, hit that share button,
let people know that the sermon is about
to begin. And um I'm going to be
speaking about something that uh I
believe will change the way that we
think.
And so with that said, let's pray and
we're going to get into the message
entitled
And it Was So. And it was so. Let's
pray. Heavenly Father, bless us, Lord,
as we open your word. Please, I pray,
Lord, that you would speak through me,
Lord, and that you would allow these
words, Lord, to affect every person who
hears.
May they who hear be a great multitude.
We pray it in Jesus name. Amen. Amen.
All
right guys, so the message was not
entitled technical difficulties. The
message again is entitled and it was so.
And now we are about to go to our
slides. So let's go ahead pull our first
slide up. uh the title of the message
and it was so and it was so. So we're
going to begin with Genesis chapter 1
and verse one where the Bible says in
the beginning
God created the heaven and the earth and
the earth was was without form and void
and darkness was upon the face of the
deep and the spirit of God moved upon
the face of the waters and God said
let there be light and there was Right?
Please, I want you to note
that God simply spoke the word and it
was so. It was so. God said, "Let there
be light." And
the words itself
had creative power so that there was
light. Let's go ahead and keep reading.
Genesis 1 vers7 the Bible says and God
made the firmament and divided the
waters that were under the firmament
from the waters which were above the
firmament and it was so.
It was so. Genesis 1:9 and God said let
the waters under the heaven be gathered
together unto one place and let the dry
land appear. And it was so. I want you
to notice that what God said it was so.
And when he said it, it was so. Genesis
1 verse 11. And God said, "Let the earth
bring forth grass, the herb yielding
seed, and the fruit tree yielding fruit
after his kind, whose seed is in itself
upon the earth." And put those words in
a chat for me everyone. And it was so.
It was so. Genesis 1:es 14 and 15.
And God said, "Let there be firmaments
in the Let there be lights in the
firmaments of the heaven to divide the
day from the night. And let them be for
signs and for seasons and for days and
for years. And let them be for lights in
the firmament of the heaven to give
light upon the earth." And it was so. It
was so. Genesis 1 24. And God said, "Let
the earth bring forth the living
creature after his kind, and the cattle
and creeping thing, and the beast of the
earth after his kind." And it was so.
Those words, beloved, and it was so. May
these words change your life forever.
May these words alter your Christian
walk forever. Come with me to Psalm 33
and verse 6. By the word of the Lord
were the heavens made and all the hosts
of them by the breath of his mouth. So
we see here that the word of the Lord
is what is behind creation. The word of
the Lord, God said it and it was so.
Verse 9 of chapter 33 of the book of
Psalms. For he spake and it was done. He
commanded
and it stood fast. This is absolutely
crucial to understand beloved. It was
so. He spake and it was done. In Hebrews
11:3, the Bible says here, "Through
faith, we understand that the worlds
were framed by the word of God, so that
things which are seen were not made of
things which do appear." Again, Psalm
148:5, "Let them praise the name of the
Lord, for he commanded and they were
created." I want you to understand the
power of the word of God.
When God speaks it, it is so. When God
speaks it, it is so.
In fact, note with me Romans chapter 4:1
17. Romans chapter 4:1 17. It says, "As
it is written, I have made thee a father
of many nations," speaking of Abraham,
"befor him whom he believed, even God
who quickenth the dead, and calleth
those things which be not as though they
were." God's word is so powerful
that if God promises something, then the
promise, the very word of him speaking
the promise brings the thing into
existence
at the time
at the time that he desires the thing to
come into existence. So when he said,
"Abraham, you're going to have a child."
Had God intended for Abraham uh and
Sarah to have that child at the moment
he spoke the word, they would have had a
child. At the moment he spoke the word.
But God intended for that child to come
upon the scene much later. And so God
speaks the word and at the appointed
time the thing comes to pass. Y'all put
a one in the chat if you understand the
concept that I just said. If God had
just said,
"Abraham and Sarah,
you have a child."
In that instant,
it would have been, what's the word I'm
looking for, everyone?
It would have been
so.
So, please again, just note with me the
power of God's word. We're talking about
the power of God's word. The creative
power of God's word is is essential for
us to understand.
Now, now that we've set the foundation
there, I now want to introduce you to
Jesus in the flesh. This is this is that
part of the sermon. And I want you to
note with me John 1 verse one. So the
Bible says here, in the beginning was
the word and the word was with God and
the word was God. The same was in the
beginning with God. The same was in the
beginning with God. Now I appreciate
what the slide team is doing here
because they are reaching out to all
nationalities. And I just caught that.
Last week it was uh uh it was China was
the country. This week it's Jamaica. I
like that. That's That's creative. Slide
team. Okay. So, in the beginning was the
word and the word was with God and the
word was God. So, now we understand. In
fact, let's go back to the screen very
quickly. It says this same was in the
beginning with God. All things were made
by him and without him was not anything
made that was made. So we now see that
Jesus Jesus the son of God
was with God.
Jesus the son of God was with God. And
now we're told that he was the word.
Meaning when he spoke when when when the
word was manifested everything was again
note with me John 1:14.
And the word was made flesh and dwelt
among us. And we beheld his glory, the
glory as of the only begotten of the
father, full of grace and truth. Full of
grace and truth. So Jesus, we're being
told in John 1:14, Jesus is the word
made flesh. He is the word made flesh.
That means
that within Jesus
is the very same power that we found at
the creation.
In fact, in Desire of Ages, page 19,
Ellen White says this, "By coming to
dwell with us, Jesus was to reveal both
God to men and to angels.
He was the word of God. God's thought
made audible.
Wow,
that is a powerful statement, y'all.
God's thought made audible. In other
words,
Jesus
is the thought of God made audible for
us to be able to understand God's
thoughts.
When you see Jesus, when you hear Jesus,
you are hearing the thoughts of God. Now
what I want to show you beloved is that
Jesus in himself possessed the same word
power
that we find in Genesis chapter 1. Let
me demonstrate to you. Let's go to the
book of Matthew chapter 1 and verse 40.
I'm sorry, Mark 1 and verse 40. Mark
chapter 1 and verse 40. And there came a
leper to him, beseeching him, and
kneeling down to him, and saying unto
him, If thou wilt, thou can make me
clean. And Jesus moved with compassion,
put forth his hand, and touched him, and
saith unto him,
I will
be thou clean.
And
sometime after he had spoken,
my bad. Many years after he had spoken,
my fault.
Few hours later after he had spoken. No.
And as soon as he had spoken,
immediately
it was so. Y'all put that in the chat
for me, please. Immediately
it was so.
It was so. Immediately the leprosy
departed from him and he was cleansed
immediately. Let me show you another
one. Mark chapter 4 verse 38 and 39. And
he was in the hinder part of the ship
asleep on a pillow. And they awake him
and say unto him, Master, carest thou
not that we perish? And he a arose and
rebuked the wind and said unto the sea,
peace be still.
And it was so.
It was so. The winds ceased and there
was a great calm. I need you to
understand that in Jesus was the very
same power creative power we find in the
book of Genesis
that it was so power that it was so word
again
Luke 7:14 and 15 I'm going somewhere
with this please follow carefully
he he came and touched the buyer and
they that bear him stood still and he
said young man, I say unto thee, arise.
And he that was dead sat up and began to
speak. In other words, it was so. And he
delivered him to his mother.
Please understand
that as soon as Jesus speaks the word,
it is so.
It is so.
And now here comes
the part that begins the transformation
because I want to take you to John
chapter 2 verse one. John chapter 2
verse one.
And now get ready for this y'all. Are
y'all ready? Somebody put a put a eight
in the chat if you're ready for what
you're about to hear next. Because what
you're about to hear next
is just absolutely
This is the lynch pin, y'all. This is
everything in this sermon and your life
changing hinges upon what you're about
to hear. John chapter 2 verse one. And
the third day third day there was a
marriage in Canaa of Galilee. And the
mother of Jesus was there. And both
Jesus was called and his disciples to
the marriage. And they wanted wine. The
mother of Jesus saith unto him, "They
have no wine."
Jesus saith unto her, "Woman, what have
I to do with thee? My hour is not yet
come." His mother saith unto his
servants, "Whatsoever he saith unto you,
do it."
Whatsoever he saith unto you, do it.
Whatsoever he saith unto you, do it. And
there were set there six water pots of
stone. And the man of the purifying of
the Jews containing two or three firings
a piece.
Jesus saith unto them, "Fill the water
pots with water." And they filled them
up to the brim. And he saith unto them,
"Draw out now, and bear unto the
governor of the feast, and they bear
it." And when the ruler of the feast had
tasted the water that was made wine, he
knew not whence it was. But the servants
which drew the water knew, the governor
of the feast called the bridegroom, and
saith unto him, "Every man at the
beginning does set forth good wine, and
when men have well drunk, than that
which is worse. But thou hast kept the
good wine until now." This beginning of
miracles did Jesus in Canaa of Galilee
and manifest manifested forth his glory
and his disciples believed on him. All
right.
What does Jesus do here? What is the
miracle?
What is the miracle here?
Y'all help me out. What is the miracle
that takes place here?
Jesus does what? He turns the water
into wine,
right?
He turns the water into wine. Now, let
me ask you something, guys. Um, how does
Jesus turn the water into wine?
How does Jesus turn the water into wine?
So, I know there's a little bit of delay
and I'm just I'm just going to wait for
you. It's okay. I'm just going to wait
for you. How does Jesus turn the water
into wine?
Okay. So, MP says he spoke
uh Patty says they obeyed
uh by his word. All right. by his word.
Now, here's my question for you. Where
in the text, where in the text does does
Jesus say, "Turn the water into wine?"
Where in the text does Jesus say, "Turn
the water into wine?"
He does not say it in the text.
All that happens in the text is Jesus
says to the servants,
"Do this.
Fill the water pots with water."
Now somewhere the water turned to wine.
And the question is how? Because Jesus
did not speak out loud,
but he spoke somewhere. Yes, blessing.
It was a thought.
It was a thought. In other words, Jesus
thought it.
He thought it and it was done. He didn't
tell anyone what he was doing. Not
according to the text. He just said,
"Fill this with water."
Which means then
that Jesus does not need to audibly
speak for the thing to happen.
the word of God
just thinking a thing.
Wow.
You talk about power
to just think it and it happens.
Let's prove this. Let's go to the book
of John 11 verse 41-42. So remember this
is the resurrection of Lazarus. The
Bible says, "Then they took away the
stone from the place where the dead was
laid. And Jesus lifted up his his eyes
and said, "Father, I thank thee that
thou has heard me.
And I knew that thou hearest me always.
But because of the people would stand
by, I said it, that they may believe
that thou has sent me."
Did y'all catch that just now?
Jesus prays to the father. He's like,
"All right, I know you already heard me.
Father, I know I know you already heard
my thought,
but I'm just going to speak out loud so
that the people can hear me when I say
the thing. So that they may know and
understand
that
that my word has power.
So if I were just to think in my mind,
Lazarus, wake up.
They may not know to attribute that to
me.
So for your sakes, I need to speak it.
Y'all put a five in the chat if you
understand what we just heard.
For your sake, I'm going to speak it so
that you can hear,
which means, beloved,
that way back there in creation, when we
read about God said, "Let there be
light."
It was not necessary for God to even
open his mouth to speak.
See beloved, don't you and I talk all
the time without using our mouths?
Don't we talk in our hearts? Don't we
think within ourselves? Don't we speak
within ourselves?
Jesus is the word of God. Had Jesus
thought in that moment, everybody wake
up. Just imagine. Had Jesus thought in
that moment, everybody wake up. What
would have happened?
Everybody would have woken up.
Now watch this. This means that Jesus
had to control his thoughts.
Wow.
Jesus would have had to control his
thoughts and direct his thoughts. Okay,
thoughts.
Only Lazarus wake up.
That's right. The cemetery would have
been empty.
Every grave would have been empty.
So then I need you to understand this
then that the burden that was upon Jesus
was greater than you and I can imagine
because Jesus had to be careful of every
single thought that he entertained.
Y'all put a five in the chat if you
understood what I just said.
Jesus had to be careful of every thought
that he entertained.
one careless thought.
Luke 4:1. Notice with me, Luke 4:1. And
Jesus being full of the Holy Ghost,
returned from Jordan, and was led by the
spirit into the wilderness, being 40
days tempted of the devil. And in those
days, he did eat nothing. And when they
were ended, after he afterward hungered,
and the devil said unto him, "If thou be
the son of God, command this stone that
it be made bread." Now, here's what I
need y'all to understand. You you guys,
had Jesus
for a moment been like, "Yeah,
let me turn the stone to bread." Had he
thought that for a moment?
Are y'all catching what I'm saying here?
Had Jesus in his mind for a second
thought, "Yes,
I'm starving.
Let me turn this bread into wine." it. I
mean, let me turn this stone into bread.
It would have been so
it would have been so.
And now you can begin to understand the
the heavy burden that must have been on
Jesus
because his thought had power.
That's right, Keith. He couldn't even
think it or it would have happened. Now,
don't get me wrong. I'm not saying that
in his mind he could not be tempted
because he was tempted as all of us are.
But had he for a moment entertained the
temptation and said, "Yes, man. I would
really like to do this."
Can you imagine?
Can you imagine? Listen to this. Let me
show you how how.
Come with me to Luke chapter 9. Luke
chapter 9:53 and 54. The Bible says,
"And they did not receive him because
his face was as though he would go to
Jerusalem." And when his disciples James
and John saw this, they they said,
"Lord,
wilt thou that we command fire to come
down from heaven and consume them even
as Elias did."
Now, pause for a moment and I want you
to think just for a moment.
When when James and John say this to
Jesus,
had Jesus
for a moment been like, "That's a good
idea.
I approve of this idea.
I consent
to this idea."
What would have happened in the instant
that Jesus consented to the idea
to have fire come down from heaven and
consume them?
Are y'all catching the significance?
Are you catching the significance
of what you're hearing right now?
Let me show you Colossians chapter
1:16-1 17. The Bible says, "All things
were created by him and for him, and he
is before all things, and by him all
things consist."
Meaning
in Jesus, everything that consists,
everything that is, is held together by
him. by his thoughts.
Therefore, all he needs to do,
all he needs to do
is to think you out of existence
and you would be thought out of
existence.
Did you all hear that?
If all things consist in him, in fact,
let's look at Hebrews chapter 1:3.
Hebrews chapter 1:3 who being the
brightness of his glory and the express
image of his person and upholding all
things by the word of his power. By the
word of his all things are upheld by the
word of his power.
Therefore
all it would take is a thought.
The same word that he thinks in his
mind. The same word. He doesn't have to
give an audible. All he has to do is
think it. By that same process,
all he would need to do is to think you
out of existence and you are gone. Like
a like a finger snap,
Terry.
Like a finger snap.
Remember this. Remember in John 18
verse4 as Jesus is about to be taken
captive and the Bible says uh Jesus
therefore knowing all things that should
come come upon him went forth and he
said unto them whom seek ye they
answered Jesus of Nazareth. Jesus saith
unto him I am he.
And Judas also which betrayed him stood
with them. And as soon as he had said
that unto them, I am he. They went
backward and fell to the ground. Do you
understand that Jesus could have said I
am he and in the thought of I want I am
he to destroy you because all he wanted
there was to say I want I am he to let
you know that I am God.
So I'm just going to allow a little bit
of the power of I am he. like a mini
mini mini many mini fraction of the word
I am he just to just so you could see
that when you take me captive you're not
really taking me captive you have no
power over me at all
because had he said I am he in full
power and in full thought of I am
you in the presence of I am will destroy
you in that instant
They would have been destroyed
in that instant. They would have been
destroyed.
And so, so this sets the stage then,
beloved, for everything else you're
about to see.
Because watch this. Let's go to Matthew
chap 26:47.
And while he spake, lo Judas, one of the
twel came, and with him a great
multitude with swords and staffs
from chief priests and the elders of the
people. Now he that betrayed betrayed
him gave them a sign, saying, Whomsoever
I shall kiss, the same is he, hold him
fast, hold him fast.
And forth with he came to Jesus, and
said, Hail, Master, and kissed him. And
Jesus said unto him, "Friend, where art
thou come?" Hold on. Can we pause for a
second? Can we pause for a second?
How many of you, as I'm reading these
words, your minds are being blown right
now?
You've read these words before. We've
all read these words before. But I just
want to want to ask, how many of you as
I'm reading these words with no
commentary, I'm just reading the words.
How many of you are like,
"What in the world?" Come on, let's keep
reading. Let's keep reading.
So Jesus said unto him, "Friend,
wherefore art thou come?" Then came they
and laid hands on Jesus, and took him.
And behold, one of them which were with
Jesus stretched stretched out his hand,
and drew his sword, and struck off a
servant of the high priest, and smold
off his ear. Then said Jesus unto him,
"Put up again thy sword into his place.
For all they that take the sword shall
perish with the sword. Thinkkest thou
that I cannot now pray to my father."
Just a thought, just a thought, and he
shall presently give me more than 12
legions of angels. But how then shall
shall the scriptures be fulfilled that
thus it must be?
In that same hour, said Jesus to the
multitude, are you come out against me
as as a thief with swords and stavs for
toetate me? I sat daily with you in the
temple, and ye laid no hold on me. But
all this was done that the scriptures of
the prophets might be fulfilled. Then
all the disciples forsook him and fled.
Y'all listen to me. Listen to me.
I want you to imagine the temptation
now before y'all may have y'all may have
thought had Jesus just spoken the word
you guys be destroyed like it takes
effort to like you know what let me say
it out loud. No no no no no no.
Had Jesus at any moment entertained the
thought
for these enemies to be destroyed
in that instant they would have been
destroyed.
Are y'all getting this?
Are y'all catching this? Let's keep
going. Matthew 26:62 and 63. And the
high priest arose and said and said unto
him, "Answerest thou nothing? What is it
which these witness against thee?" But
Jesus held his peace.
Does that give a new meaning to you?
That Jesus held his peace.
When I was reading that this morning,
I thought to myself, I've always read
this verse, Jesus held his peace as
Jesus didn't respond to what they were
saying or Jesus was like, you know what,
I'm just going to be quiet. I've always
looked at the verse like that way. He
held his peace.
But beloved, now I'm understanding
that in this case, Jesus was controlling
himself
because
all he had to do was think, "I don't
like you guys."
All he had to do was think, "I don't
like you guys." And you understand that
when you hate someone in your heart, let
me let me pause on that for a second.
In Isaiah 53:7, he was oppressed. He was
afflicted, yet he opened not his mouth.
Do you understand that? The reason he
opened not his mouth. Now, I need Come
back. Come back for a moment. Come back
for a moment. I need you to understand
we have two mouths. How many of you know
that we have two mouths?
How many of you understand that we have
two mouths? We have this mouth
and we have this mouth
or this mouth, right? Wherever you want
to go. The the inner mouth and the mouth
of the flesh.
And so for many of us, we think
that in not speaking through the mouth
of the flesh, we're good. But God hears
the thoughts.
Had Jesus inwardly thought for a moment,
I don't like these guys and they need to
suffer for what they are doing to me. In
that moment,
the Pharisees and the Sadducees and the
leaders would have been dead.
They would have been dead. Let's keep
going. Let's keep going. The Bible says
in Luke 6:45, "A good man out of the
good treasure of his heart bringeth
forth that that which is good, and an
evil man out of the evil treasure of his
heart bringeth forth that which is evil.
For of the abundance of the heart, the
mouth speaketh." The the mouth speaks
out of the abundance of the heart
because the heart speaks first. The
heart speaks first.
Listen to this.
The Jews were continually seeking for
and expecting a divinity among them that
would be revealed in outward show. And
by one flash of overmastering will
change the current of all minds, force
from them an acknowledgment of his
superiority, elevate himself, and
gratify the ambition of his people.
This being the case,
when Christ was treated with contempt,
there was a powerful temptation before
him to reveal his heavenly character and
to compel his persecutors to admit that
he was Lord above kings and potentates,
priests and temple. But it was his
difficult task to maintain the level of
humanity.
Do y'all understand this church?
Do y'all understand the significance
the significance of what
of what we are seeing here?
had Jesus for an instant
been like, "You know what? I'm done with
y'all."
You know how we often do
with people who get on our nerves
had Jesus for a moment. Now, why did
Jesus not do that for a moment? Listen,
listen y'all. It is because he
understood the power of his thoughts
and understanding the the the the the
power of his thoughts. He didn't take
his thoughts lightly.
Listen to this. Listen to this. Desire
of Ages page 700. He knew that in a
moment, by the flashing forth of his
divine power, he could lay his cruel
tormentors in the dust. This made the
trial harder to bear. Wow.
Wow.
Jesus knew
that had he merely thought,
it would have been so.
It would have been so.
Let's keep reading, y'all. Matthew 27
27-28. Then the soldiers of the governor
took Jesus into the common hall and
gathered unto him the whole band of
soldiers, and they stripped him and put
on him a scarlet robe.
And when they had platted a crown of
thorns, they put it upon his head, and a
reed in his right hand, and they bowed
the knee before him, and mocked him,
saying, "Hail, King of the Jews." And
they spit on him, and took the reed and
smote him on the head. And after that he
had mocked And after that they had
mocked him, they took the robe off from
him and put his put him in his own
raignment and they led him away to
crucify him.
I need y'all
to put yourself in Jesus's place for a
moment with Jesus's power.
And tell me if I'm lying
when I say that these verses would never
have been in existence.
How many of you having Jesus's power
would have endured what he endured?
How many of you would have been like,
notice I didn't say anything. So, I'm
I'm I'm trying to show you what I'm
thinking.
How many of you
think about bearing that kind of
responsibility?
Matthew 27:38.
Then were the two thieves crucified with
him, the one on the right hand, the
other on the left. And they that passed
by reviled him, wagging their heads,
saying, "Thou that destroyed the temple,
build it in three days, save thyself. If
thou be the son of God, come down from
the cross. Likewise also the chief
priests mocking him with the scribes and
elders said he saved others himself he
cannot save. If he be the king himself
he cannot save. Do you understand how
they are talking all of this let's say
garbage not realizing that Jesus with a
with one thought of anger could have
could have ended their existence.
And now may this verse
ring in a new way to you. Here we go.
Here it is on the screen.
For God so loved the world that he gave
his only begotten son
that whosoever believeth on him should
not perish but have everlasting life.
May that verse,
May that verse ring new to you.
Because what I want you to understand,
beloved,
is that the thing that kept Jesus
from thinking evil towards us. You know
the Bible says, "I know the thoughts
that I have towards you, thoughts of
peace and not of evil." Had Jesus
entertained thoughts of evil,
we would have been gone. What is it that
prevented him from entertaining thoughts
of evil? His love for us.
Wow.
It was love that led Jesus to guard his
every thought because he knew that one
thought could destroy us.
This is why John 14:30 Jesus could say
this hereafter I will not talk much with
you for the prince of this world cometh
and has nothing in me. Has how much in
me? Nothing in me. Nothing in me. That
means Jesus. Let me let me let me let El
White say it. The prince of this world
cometh and has nothing in me. There was
in him nothing that responded to Satan's
sophistry. He did not consent to to sin.
Not even by a thought did he yield to
temptation. Do you understand why now?
temptation. See, I've read this this
statement before. Not even by a thought
was Jesus led to led to sin. And I've
always looked at that that phrase, not
even by a thought was Jesus led to sin.
That it was just like, no, I'm not
sinning.
Any anybody ever had that like, no, I'm
not I'm not sinning anymore. You can't
get me to sin. I'm not going to sin. I'm
not going to think a bad thought and
then have to, you know, just be like, oh
man, I've sinned and fallen. I'm not
going to do that. I've always just
looked at it as, you know, Jesus just he
just wasn't he just wasn't playing. He
was about his father's business. He
wasn't playing. But beloved, now I
understand that the reason he did not
even yield to sin in his thought is
because he knew one wrong thought,
one thought of yielding to to the to the
enemy, one thought of anger towards us,
one thought of forsaking us would have
destroyed all of humanity.
And it was his love.
It was his love that led him not to
entertain that thought. Watch this.
It was not Lord help me. How am I going
to say this?
What kept him
from not sinning in thought
is also available to us.
What motivated Jesus was love.
Wow.
What motivated Jesus
was love. Listen, even back in heaven,
God could have destroyed Desire of Ages,
page 759. God could have destroyed Satan
and his sympathizers as easily as one
can cast a pebble to the earth, but he
did not do this. When Jesus is on the
cross and his enemies are surrounding
him and they're mocking him and they're
spitting upon him and they're beating
him and all of these things, Jesus is
following the example of his father.
Jesus is showing who he was before he
came manifest in the flesh. He's showing
himself in the flesh. This is who I am.
This is love. Y'all don't understand
right now. You're doing this and that.
Y'all don't even understand that one
simple thought could destroy you. But I
love you too much to think evil against
you.
All right.
Now, it's time to bring this sermon to
us.
Philippians chapter 2 verse 5,
let this mind be in you which was also
in Christ Jesus. We could stop right
there. We could stop right there.
Let this mind be in you which was also
in Christ Jesus.
Do you understand the significance
of this verse in light of what we've
just read? In other words, God is
saying,
I want you to have the mind that
understands that to to to think
something is for it to be so.
And though you don't have the power of
divinity to carry out immediately what
you think, you don't have that power.
You can't think a thing and it is so
immediately. No, no, no, no, no. You
think a thing and then you need time and
effort to bring that thing to pass.
But nonetheless, I need you to
understand that once you think the
thing, it is as good as so.
Have you ever killed anyone? No. Have
you ever killed anyone?
Put a one in the chat if you ever killed
somebody.
Put a one in the chat if you have ever
killed someone. Listen to me y'all.
There will be people in the judgment who
will be condemned for murder,
never having thought that they murdered
anybody.
Proverbs 23
verse 7.
For as he thinkketh in his heart,
for as he thinkketh in his heart,
the text says so is he. I'm going to say
it is so.
It is. So,
beloved, do you understand how that
changes things for us? I think we've
heard it before. You know, um Jesus says
in Matthew chapter 5 27, for example,
you have heard that it was said by them
of old that thou shalt not commit
adultery, but I say unto you that
whosoever lookth on a woman to lust
after her has committed adultery already
with her in his heart.
We've read this verse
and maybe we've thought of it as a well
okay I mean you know doesn't really mean
that you've committed already it just
means that you know it's as good as you
listen to me
let this mind be in you which was also
in Christ Jesus the mind Christ Jesus
had was the mind that said if I think
the thing And it is so understand
beloved that if we start entering if we
start walking in our Christian walk with
that responsibility with that burden
that if I think the thing it is so do
you understand how many how many how
much do you understand how much less
Lord help me to phrase this right? Do
you understand how many fewer enemies we
would have? Do you understand how many
fewer people we would hate?
Do you understand
how many fewer people we would say in
our minds, in our hearts, I hate that
guy. I hate that girl. I hate this
person. Why? Because the Bible says,
listen to this. The Bible says in 1 John
3:15, "Whosoever hateth his brother is a
murderer."
Wow.
Whosoever hateth his brother is a
murderer.
Think about you guys how many crimes
you're guilty of. Think of this. If you
had the power of Jesus and now y'all
know, for those of you that watched the
Sabbath school last week, you now know,
you know where this sermon is coming
from. Because when we had that
discussion about the power of the
thoughts and the snapping if we had the
power of Jesus, how many of us would
snap our fingers in our minds to get rid
of other people?
How many of us would snap our fingers
to cheat on our spouses?
How many of us would snap on our our
snap our fingers to steal and to if by a
thought you could have your neighbor's
car?
How many of you would be ever so more
careful to know as a Christian if I
think that that neighbor's without the
car and now I have his car and here I am
walking around with his car and I feel
guilty because he knows I wanted his car
and now I have it because my thoughts
have power.
Just because we cannot bring our
thoughts to pass like Jesus can doesn't
mean that we are not guilty of the sin.
Most of us
are only held back by the lack of
opportunity to do the thing that we've
already committed mentally to.
So we haven't stolen. Why? because we
really just don't want to get caught.
But if we had the opportunity to
without getting caught, if we had the
opportunity to do that thing without
getting caught, we would do that thing.
If we had the opportunity to to indulge
that thought without anybody know, we
would do that thing.
But now we're beginning to understand,
wait a minute, when I think it, it is
so.
And now that I'm walking around with
that burden of, and it was so, now I'm
realizing just how careful I need to be
in my thoughts, which is why 2
Corinthians chapter 10:es 3-5 tell us
this. For though we walk in the flesh,
we do not war after the flesh. For the
weapons of our warfare are not carnal,
but mighty through God to the pulling
down of strongholds, casting down what?
Imaginations,
and every high thing that exaltth itself
against the knowledge of God, and
bringing into captivity every thought to
the obedience
of Christ.
every thought.
Now I'm understanding why my thoughts
have power.
They don't have the kind of power that
God's thoughts have. But now when I
begin to understand, let this mind be in
you which was also in Christ Jesus. The
mind of Christ refused to think evil
because he knew that the mere thought
would bring it to pass.
He knew that had he enter had he
entertained a thought of hate.
We would have been done.
And now let me read that statement again
from the desire of ages page 123. The
prince of this world cometh said Jesus
and has nothing in me. There was nothing
in him. There was in him nothing that
responded to Satan's sophistry. He did
not consent to sin. Not even by a
thought did he yield to temptation. so
it may be with us. Christ's humanity was
united with divinity. He was fitted for
the conflict by the indwelling of the
Holy Spirit and he came to make us
partakers of the divine nature. So long
as we are united to him by faith, sin
has no more dominion over us. God
reaches for the hand of faith in us to
direct it to lay fast the whole fast
hold upon the divinity of Christ that we
may attain to perfection of character.
And now beloved again you can
understand. Wait a minute.
Just think about this.
If I had an evil thought to my child,
that thought would make my child
disappear.
Now, how many of you would have children
who disappear?
Not one.
Love would prevent you from ever
thinking an evil thought. If the love of
God is dwelling in you, it would prevent
you from thinking an evil thought to
your children,
to your spouse,
to your neighbors,
to God.
Therefore, beloved, love is the key
thing.
Did you all catch that?
If you have the power
right now
if the way mankind was was in the image
of God in the sense of if I think this
evil that person disappears.
If that burden was on you
and the rule was all that needs to
happen is you need to be mad at that
person, you need to hate that person.
You need to not like that person and
that person disappears. How many of you
would from this day forward be like,
"Okay, I may not like what you're doing.
I may not like what you said."
And that's fine, but I'm not going to
hate you in my heart. Because if I hate
you in my heart, then you disappear
and then I'm guilty of killing. So
because I love God and he has told me to
love you, my love for you, even though
you're spitting on me and beating me and
taking advant
I'm not going to hate you.
Remember how sin started? How does sin
start?
Isaiah 14:13. We're almost done, you
guys. We're almost done. Isaiah 14:13.
How did sin start? For thou has said,
with your mouth.
For thou has said, with your mouth.
No, no, no, no. For thou hast said, in
thine heart, I will ascend into heaven.
I will exalt my throne above the stars
of God. I will sit also upon the mount
of the congregation in the size of the
north. What if Lucifer had the power of
God? In the moment that he said, I will
ascend into heaven. I will exalt my
throne above the stars of God. I will
sit also upon the mount of the
congregation. In that very moment, God
would have been gone.
But Lucifer did not have the power of
God.
So time and circumstance held Lucifer's
thoughts back from coming to full
fruition. They took time. He had to
exert effort to bring his thoughts to
pass.
Not so with God.
So beloved, when we think a thing, you
got to understand that the thing that we
think, if the devil can bring about the
right circumstances, that thing is going
to come to pass. Most of the times, half
of the things we think and we we desire
after don't come to pass simply because
we don't have the opportunity.
But if you were put in the opportunity
and your mind has already made up the
decision weeks ago, months ago, years
ago,
this is why Hebrews chapter 4:12 tells
us this. For the word of God is quick
and powerful and sharper than any
two-edged sword, piercing even to the
desi dividing a sunder of soul and
spirit and of the joints and marrow and
is a discerner of the thoughts and
intents of the heart. Y'all catching
this? Come on. I just got a few more few
more verses and we're done. Let us hear
the conclusion of the whole matter. Fear
God and keep his commandments for this
is the whole duty of man. For God shall
bring every work into judgment with
every secret thing, whether it be good
or whether it be evil. Now you can begin
to understand, beloved, why a text in
the Bible like this exists. My son,
forget not my law, but let thine heart
keep my commandments.
Let thine heart keep my commandments.
There's a reason why God wants the law
written on your hearts. Jeremiah 31:33.
This is the covenant that I will make
with the house of Israel after those
days, sayeth the Lord, I will put my law
in their inward parts and write them in
their hearts and will be their God and
they shall be my people. In other words,
beloved, God wants the law to be to
operate on the thought level.
Many of us keep the law on the flesh
level. All right? I'm not gonna
physically take your stuff, okay? I'm
not gonna physically kill you. All
right? But beloved, Jesus, when he came,
he said, "Listen, I need you to
understand that
that is not what counts. It counts."
Yes. But if that's all you're focused on
to the exclusion of the law being
written
actually in the heart,
meaning I realize
that my thoughts must be guided by the
law. And now it's no longer a matter of
I can't do this because I don't want to
sin. No, it's a matter of whoa, if I
hate this brother, then he's dead.
I've killed him. Yeah, he still walk
around in the flesh, but it is as though
I have killed him. And I'm not a
murderer. I'm a Christian.
No, I'm not murdering him. You want me
to do what? Satan, you want me to do
what? You want me to murder him? Nah,
not happening.
Not happening. I'm a follower of Jesus.
You want me to steal that guy's car? You
want me to steal his house?
Nope. Why would I do that?
Why would I do that?
You You You actually want me to go kill
him? No. No. Just think it. Just think
it and he's dead. No.
No. I'm I can be upset at what he's
doing, but No.
No, I'm not going to think evil.
I will not entertain you, Satan, even in
thought.
And now the burden of having to be like,
"Okay, how can I overcome sin? How can I
do how can I No, now that burden is
gone. And now all you realize is, hey,
if I have love in my heart, I am not
going to think evil against my neighbor.
I'm not going to tr try to take my
neighbor's stuff.
I'm not going to have anger towards Noah
because that's not who I am. I'm a
Christian. I'm not perfect.
But I'm a Christian. I'm a follower of
Jesus and I'm just not. If God if if if
God is going to call me perfect, let let
him call me perfect. All I know is that
I'm not going to kill you and I'm not
going to bear false witness against you
and I'm not going to hate you. I'm not
going to cover it against you. No, I'm
not just not going to do those things.
I'm not saved on my own righteousness
because I my righteousness are as filthy
rats. But I can tell you this. I will
not entertain you even in thought,
Satan. I just won't do it.
1 Peter chapter chapter 2 verse one. We
got two more verses after this. We are
done. For even here unto were you
called, because Christ also suffered for
us, leaving us an example that you
should follow in his steps. Who did no
sin, neither was Gile found in his
mouth. See those two different things.
Who did no sin, neither was Gile found
in his mouth, neither of his mouth, not
the fleshly mouth and not the mouth of
his mind. Watch this. Who when he was
reviled, reviled not again.
When he suffered, he threatened not
because had he threatened, they would
have been gone. But he committed himself
to him that judges righteously, who in
his own self bear our sins in his own
body on the tree, that we being dead to
sin should live unto righteousness, by
whose stripes we are healed. You guys,
this is I hope you see this is
revolutionary, mindblowing, mindchanging
stuff.
Now we can understand why the seal of
God in Revelation 7 is placed
in the mind.
Now I understand why Revelation 7:1 the
four winds are being held back.
I saw another angel ascending from the
east having the seal of the living God.
And he cried with a loud voice to the
four angels to whom it was given to hurt
the earth and the sea, saying, "Hurt not
the earth, neither the sea nor the
trees, till we have sealed the servants
of our God in their foreheads." You're
sealed in the forehead. Meaning, I will
not entertain
any thought of harm to my neighbor.
That's it.
Wow. I will not take advantage. I will
not entertain any thought. I will not
covet. I because every one of those
every every thought is hurting somebody
else.
I won't do it.
I may have my issues. I may have my
struggles. I know. But here's one thing
I'm not going to do. Satan, I'm not
going to entertain your thoughts. And
you will find that in not entertaining
the thoughts of Satan.
I mean, let God say it. You don't say
it, but let God say, "Have you consider
considered my servant? Have you
considered my children? How they're
faithful to me? You can't even get them
to follow you in thought."
Yes, everybody will be tempted. You'll
be tempted to think. You'll be tempted
to do all kinds of things. That's we're
human. We're all going to face
temptation.
But you could say in your mind, you know
what? As appealing as as that may may be
or look to the flesh, I'm saying no.
I'm not going to entertain it right
here. I'm not going to consent to it
right here. I've already made up my
mind. Not happening.
by the grace and power of God through
the love of Jesus. It's not happening.
Put a one in the chat if you are ready
to let this mind be in you which was in
Christ Jesus.
If you are ready to say, Lord, help me
to live as though my thoughts
have the power of life and death in
them. Help me to live Jesus with the
same burden that you lived with
so that I will not
I will not entertain the devil's
suggestions in my mind. And if I can
beat the devil here, I've already beaten
him in the flesh.
I see the ones coming in the chat. I see
the ones coming in the chat. Um,
I hope this message changes the way you
think.
think. Put it in the chat, everyone. And
it was so.
Walk with those words. No. If I hate
that brother, may as well say, "And it
was so."
Help that it was so to be for
righteousness sake, not for wickedness
sake. Help me to wish good on people.
Help me to think well of people. Help me
to love people despite sometimes their
unlovable natures. Help me, Lord, to
have the mind of Jesus. Heavenly Father,
thank you for speaking to us.
Bless us with your mind. May we carry
the burden of understanding the power of
our thoughts.
And in carrying this burden, may it
change the way we think.
May we not snap our fingers
and exercise the power of destruction
and theft and lying and adultery and
stealing and killing,
coveting.
But Lord, may we resist the enemy
because of our love for you and our love
for our neighbor.
In Jesus name we pray. Put the mind of
Jesus in us and let us live by it.
In Jesus name we pray. Amen.
Um, beloved, uh, we're going to go ahead
and put the, uh,
put the, uh, link for, uh, the the Zoom,
I'm sorry, the Mighty Networks, I'm
sorry. We're going to put the link for
the Mighty Networks, uh, into the chat
so that you could join us on Afterlow
and we can discuss the Sabbath school as
well as the sermon. And uh, I pray that
again this message uh, has touched your
life.
uh in a way that will change the way
that you see things and the way that you
walk in your Christian walk today. So,
may God bless you and uh we will see you
again next Sabbath. Please let people
know about Living Mana Church. Invite
people, tell them to get on Mighty
Networks and just see what we have going
on here um and our online church. May
you be blessed and I'll see you next
week.
Thank you for joining us today. If this
is your first time worshiping with us,
please check out our website at
livingmana.urch.
We are not just here for Sabbath
service. We have weekly programming too
that covers mental health, physical
health, weekly prayer service, financial
health, and proving the existence of
God. It is our desire that our
programming will continue to bless you.
Please continue to pray for us as we
fulfill God's mission to go into all the
world with the gospel of Jesus Christ.
[Music]